<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss  xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" 
      xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" 
      xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" 
      xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" 
      version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>Ian Beilfuss</title>
<link>https://ian88.github.io/blogPosts.html</link>
<atom:link href="https://ian88.github.io/blogPosts.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
<description></description>
<generator>quarto-1.8.26</generator>
<lastBuildDate>Sun, 11 May 2025 05:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
<item>
  <title>May 11, 2025</title>
  <dc:creator>Ian Beilfuss</dc:creator>
  <link>https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 14 Workshop II/</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 




<p>This week’s blog post will be a bit different. I didn’t travel anywhere for the weekend because my friend Carson was visiting from Ireland where he studies abroad so instead I want to talk about the block course I took this past week called Workshop II. Workshop II was a one-week hands-on course run by Professor Peter Kumble for students from CZU and Charles University (another university in Prague). The course is a requirement for Landscape Planning and Nature Conservation graduate students but it was open to exchange students as well. I signed up during the first week of the semester and was starting to regret my choice later in the semester because I didn’t want to be gone from Prague during one of my last weeks but ended up being glad I went. It was interesting to do more hands-on conservation work and refreshing to not be sitting in a classroom. I met a lot of great people and learned a thing or two as well. I wish the course had taken place earlier in the semester, it was great to make new friends but now I only have one week left in Prague and likely won’t see them again. It was also refreshing to spend a week away from my American friends and interact with more Europeans than I usually do.</p>
<p>For the workshop, we spent the week in the small Czech town of Slavonice. Slavonice has around 2300 residents and is located around a mile from the Austrian border. Historically, Slavonice was located along a main trade corridor in the Austro-Hungarian Empire, and at one point the town had a large defensive wall and mote. Now, the town mainly relies on tourism during the summer. We were told Slavonice gets quite busy but we were there a bit early because it was very empty for most of while we were there. The small town’s character and proximity to agricultural fields and forests made it a good fit for landscape planning and native conservation work. Professor Kumble has been taking his students to Slavonice for this workshop for many years so has a good understanding of the town and surrounding area and has built relationships with many people living in Slavonice. He also brought in other professors and grad students to help with our projects for the week.</p>
<p>We spent most of our time either in the field collecting data or at the Slavonice Center for the Future analyzing the data and creating our final PowerPoints. The Center of the Future is a renovated school building that now hosts company workshops, rock shows, movies, and anything else Slavonice needs.</p>
<p>For housing, the 30 students in the Workshop were spread around the town wherever there was room. I got placed in a brand new guest house a little bit off the main square with two students from Charles University: Felix from Germany, and Luca from Italy. Both of them were very nice and easy to get along with! Our guest house had two floors and a nearly full kitchen. I got lucky enough to be by myself on the first floor with a queen bed. Not bad for $25 a night.</p>
<div class="cell column-page quarto-layout-panel" data-layout-ncol="3" data-layout-nrow="1">
<div class="quarto-layout-row">
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 33.3%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 14 Workshop II/media/penzion.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>Our guest house for the week</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 33.3%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 14 Workshop II/media/bed.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>My room in the guest house</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 33.3%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 14 Workshop II/media/institute.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>Slavonice Center for the Future</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<section id="monday" class="level2 page-columns page-full">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="monday">Monday</h2>
<p>We left the Prague Main Station at 8 am this morning and headed for Slavonice. After one short train change, we arrived in Slavonice at 12:30 pm. I’m continually amazed that even some of the smallest towns in Czechia are reachable by train. Professor Kumble set everyone up in their accommodations for the week and then gave us some time for lunch. I went with Felix and Luca to a restaurant on the main square and got some pork noodles. We reconvened with the group at 3 to go in the Slavonice underground and up the lookout tower. The underground was a very unique experience. We were given rubber boots and rain jackets to put on and headed into the very narrow underground tunnels. Our guide told us the underground was originally built in the 13th century when it was used for water drainage, groundwater collection, and protection against invading armies. Now, some of the underground has been opened up to the public for short tours. Our tour was about 30 minutes long and involved crouching our way through two 50-meter stretches with a break in the middle in a larger room in the middle to learn some of the underground’s history. Crouching my way through the tunnels was probably the most confined I’ve ever been in a cave-like area. There were points when I was fully crouching and had to turn myself sideways to fit around a tight bend. Not somewhere I would want to be for extended periods. The very sporadic lighting and half a foot of water on the ground didn’t help either. Still a very unique experience that I’m glad I did. Next, we went up the clock tower in the town square. Again, it was very cramped at the top but there were great views of all of Slavonice and the surrounding area. After the tower, Professor Kumble gave us a short tour of Slavonice, pointing out the sgraffito and old outer defense wall. Sgraffito was a technique that became very popular during the 16th century in Czechia. It involves coating a wall with multiple layers of different plaster colors and then scraping away the plaster to create intricate designs. The sgraffito buildings were gorgeous.</p>
<div class="cell column-page quarto-layout-panel" data-layout-ncol="2" data-layout-nrow="4">
<div class="quarto-layout-row">
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 50.0%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 14 Workshop II/media/train.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>The cute little two car train that brought us to Slavonice</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 50.0%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 14 Workshop II/media/porknoodles.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>Pork noodles for lunch</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="quarto-layout-row">
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 50.0%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 14 Workshop II/media/underground.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>Squeezing our way through the narrow underground tunnels</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 50.0%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 14 Workshop II/media/undergroundgroup.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>We made it throught the Underground!</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="quarto-layout-row">
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 50.0%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 14 Workshop II/media/tower.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>The old clock tower that’s now an obervation tower</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 50.0%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 14 Workshop II/media/slavonice.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>Slavonice main square from the oberservation tower</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="quarto-layout-row">
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 50.0%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 14 Workshop II/media/sgraffito1.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>An example of the sgraffito</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 50.0%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 14 Workshop II/media/sgraffito2.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>Another sgraffito example</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</section>
<section id="tuesday" class="level2 page-columns page-full">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="tuesday">Tuesday</h2>
<p>Today was a long day of walking. We began by walking down one of the bicycle trails to the Austrian border. It’s so amazing that the border between Czechia and Austria is only marked by a change of signage indicating you’re now on the Austrian bike trail. We stopped many times along the way for the professors to point out important ecological areas or inform us of the history of the area. One of the notable features was all the bunkers on the Czech side. Apparently over 1000 bunkers were built in Czechia near the beginning of WWII for use against the Germans if they invaded through Austria. The bunkers were never used but proved too difficult to remove so they’ve just become part of the Czech landscape. We spent a few hours walking through the Austrian countryside, stopping occasionally to discuss the land around us and to put up motion-sensing wildlife cameras. When we crossed back into Czechia, Kumble pointed out what looked to be a thriving forest and said that this used to be a small Czech town until the Iron Curtain was formed. The town was too close to the border and could have provided Czechs with an easier location to try to escape to Austria. There was no visible evidence of the town from the path which was incredible. In general, it was amazing how little evidence of the Iron Curtain still exists in the area. No signs of the barbed border wall and associated border surveillance were evident except for some very straight military roads. We stopped for lunch at a delicious small restaurant seemingly in the middle of nowhere called Restaurace Maříž. After lunch, we continued back towards Slavonice. We stopped once on the way to look at the ruins of an old manor house. In total, we walked almost 15 miles. It was a rewarding day.</p>
<div class="cell column-page quarto-layout-panel" data-layout-ncol="2" data-layout-nrow="4">
<div class="quarto-layout-row">
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 50.0%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 14 Workshop II/media/bunker1.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>One of the Czech bunkers</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 50.0%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 14 Workshop II/media/bunker2.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>Another bunker</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="quarto-layout-row">
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 50.0%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 14 Workshop II/media/border.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>Amazing that the border can just be marked by a simple sign</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 50.0%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 14 Workshop II/media/path.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>A small walking path in the Austrian countrystide</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="quarto-layout-row">
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 50.0%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 14 Workshop II/media/pplborder.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>Crossing back into Czechia, one foot in each country</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 50.0%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 14 Workshop II/media/forest.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>A thriving forest now grows where the Czech village used to be</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="quarto-layout-row">
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 50.0%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 14 Workshop II/media/lunch.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>Lunch at Restaurace Maříž</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 50.0%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 14 Workshop II/media/oldmansion.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>The ruins of an old Czech manor</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</section>
<section id="wednesday-and-thursday" class="level2 page-columns page-full">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="wednesday-and-thursday">Wednesday and Thursday</h2>
<p>On Wednesday morning we divided up into groups of 4-6 people to work on our smaller projects depending on what topic we found most interesting during the walk on Tuesday. I chose to work with the water quality ground, analyzing the Slavonický Potok stream that flows through Slavonice. We began by taking rental bikes and biking three miles to the stream’s headwaters. We took water samples at the headwater spring and three of the nearby downstream fish ponds. On the bike ride back we stopped at the ruins of an ancient farming village. Back in Slavonice, we took water samples, before, inside, and after the village. We spent the rest of the day and most of Thursday analyzing the data, collecting more data when needed, and creating a PowerPoint displaying our findings and possible solutions. We discovered that the Slavonice Waste Water Treatment Plant was releasing very high concentrations of NO3 into the stream. We proposed the creation of a small constructed wetland to remove the NO3 but that would involve a fairly significant investment from the town. On Wednesday night the Institute hosted a cookout for the students on the Workshop and local people from Slavonice. We had a fun evening playing table tennis, pool, and cards.</p>
<div class="cell column-page quarto-layout-panel" data-layout-ncol="2" data-layout-nrow="4">
<div class="quarto-layout-row">
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 50.0%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 14 Workshop II/media/biking.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>Biking to the headwaters</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 50.0%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 14 Workshop II/media/sample.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>Felix taking a water sample</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="quarto-layout-row">
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 50.0%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 14 Workshop II/media/selfi.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>Working hard or hardly working?</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 50.0%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 14 Workshop II/media/villageruins.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>Ruins of a very old farming village</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="quarto-layout-row">
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 50.0%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 14 Workshop II/media/treatmentplant.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>The Slavonice Waste Water Treatment Plant</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 50.0%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 14 Workshop II/media/irish.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>Playing cards with our Irish friends</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="quarto-layout-row">
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 50.0%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 14 Workshop II/media/pool.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>Closing out the night with some pool</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</section>
<section id="friday" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="friday">Friday</h2>
<p>We spent most of the morning listening to the groups present on their topic. There was a lot of interesting information about riparian restoration, biocorridors, bikeways, and bird sightings. At 1 pm we took the train back to Prague in what felt like a very anticlimactic end to an enjoyable week.</p>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>Czechia</category>
  <guid>https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 14 Workshop II/</guid>
  <pubDate>Sun, 11 May 2025 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 14 Workshop II/media/cover.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>May 6, 2025</title>
  <dc:creator>Ian Beilfuss</dc:creator>
  <link>https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 13 Krakow/</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 




<p>This post will be quite a bit heavier than my past posts since it involves visiting Birkenau and Auschwitz. Both were very humbling and informative experiences, and we were all very glad we took the time to visit. That being said, we also had a lot of fun visiting Kraków, it’s an enjoyable city!</p>
<section id="friday" class="level2 page-columns page-full">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="friday">Friday</h2>
<p>We took the overnight RegioJet bus from Prague to Kraków. After doing the same to get to Budapest, I thought we agreed to not do it again, yet here we were. The RegioJet was more comfortable than the FlixBus, but the 30-minute layover to switch buses in Brno guaranteed that I slept minimally. We arrived blurry-eyed in Krakow at 6:30. After dropping our stuff at Greg and Tom’s Beer House Hostel, we went to grab breakfast at a small cafe. I had a delicious chocolate croissant and proceeded to fall asleep almost instantly, and I wasn’t the only one. We spent the morning at Wawel Royal Castle, one of the major Kraków castles. The Castle is famous for representing almost all major European architectural styles, which was very cool to see. The metal dragon in front of the castle was also quite the sight, especially since it breathed fire every five minutes. For lunch, we found a small kimbap restaurant. I think this might have been my first time having kimbap, and I definitely enjoyed it. Next stop was the Bunny Cafe. For $5, we got half an hour to sit and hang out with bunnies in the cafe. They gave us shoe coverings and a cup of grass to feed the bunnies. Many of them were quite shy, but others happily took the food. They were also enormous! Probably the largest bunnies I’ve ever seen. Such an entertaining thing to find in the middle of Kraków. We spent the afternoon in the salt mines and then came back for dinner at Restauracja Smakotyki. I ordered the meat dumplings, but was a bit underwhelmed, finding a place with perogies on the menu would have been a better bet.&nbsp;</p>
<div class="cell column-page quarto-layout-panel" data-layout-ncol="2" data-layout-nrow="4">
<div class="quarto-layout-row">
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 50.0%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 13 Krakow/media/regiojet.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>Taking the overnight RegioJet was not ideal for sleep</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 50.0%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 13 Krakow/media/croissant.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>Chocolate croissant for breakfast might be the best croissant I’ve had abroad yet</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="quarto-layout-row">
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 50.0%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 13 Krakow/media/selfi.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>Arrival selfi in Wawel Royal Castle</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 50.0%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 13 Krakow/media/dragon.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>Wawel Dragon, it spits real fire every 5 minutes!</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="quarto-layout-row">
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 50.0%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 13 Krakow/media/castle1.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>The many domes of Wawel Royal Castle</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 50.0%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 13 Krakow/media/castle2.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>Inner castle garden</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="quarto-layout-row">
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 50.0%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 13 Krakow/media/kimbap.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>Kimbap lunch</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 50.0%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 13 Krakow/media/bunny1.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>Bunny cafe!</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="quarto-layout-row">
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 50.0%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 13 Krakow/media/bunny2.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>Artemis at bunny cafe, this bunny was absolutely enormous</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 50.0%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 13 Krakow/media/dumplings.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>Dumpling dinner at Restauracja Smakotyki</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<section id="salt-mines" class="level3 page-columns page-full">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="salt-mines">Salt Mines</h3>
<p>Wieliczka Salt Mine was incredible! This is a must-see if you visit Krakow, and it was an especially perfect thing to do on the very rainy day we had. They offered the Tourist Route or the Miners Route. Unfortunately, the Miners Route was sold out for the day, but the Tourist Route was still great. They paired about 30 of us with an English tour guide, and we descended over 25 flights of stairs to 64 meters below ground. At the deepest point of the tour I think we were over 120 meters below ground. The tour was a bit overcrowded, so it was hard to hear and felt a bit rushed at times, but we still learned a lot about the mining culture, the pulley system for extracting the rock salt, the immense wooden scaffolding required to keep shafts open, and how the mine evolved. One of the most interesting facts was how the miners would carry lit torches into mined corridors to burn off the methane released while mining before it got to lethal or explosive levels. There were a bunch of cool rock salt sculptures along the tour, but by far the most amazing part was the salt cathedral. The miners wanted somewhere to worship while in the mines, so they built a bunch of small chapels throughout the mines and one large cathedral in a huge open room. It was jaw-dropping. The cathedral walls were lined with murals carved by miners depicting religious scenes like the Last Supper, and the chandeliers were created from thousands of small salt pieces. The tour lasted around three hours, and it’s safe to say we were all incredibly impressed.&nbsp;</p>
<div class="cell column-page quarto-layout-panel" data-layout-ncol="2" data-layout-nrow="4">
<div class="quarto-layout-row">
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 50.0%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 13 Krakow/media/walkdown.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>25 flights of stairs down</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 50.0%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 13 Krakow/media/64meters.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>The stairs ended 64 meters below the surface, the deepest point of the tour was 120 meters below</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="quarto-layout-row">
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 50.0%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 13 Krakow/media/pullysystem.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>Horses were used to pull this elaborate system to bring large cylinders of mined rock salt up one level at a time</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 50.0%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 13 Krakow/media/saltcathedral.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>Salt Cathedral</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="quarto-layout-row">
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 50.0%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 13 Krakow/media/saltsupper.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>The Last Supper carved in rock salt</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 50.0%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 13 Krakow/media/saltlake.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>underground salt lake, 9 meters deep in some places</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="quarto-layout-row">
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 50.0%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 13 Krakow/media/saltstructure.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>It’s hard to imagine how much structural engineering work went into building this 100 meters deep</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</section>
</section>
<section id="saturday" class="level2 page-columns page-full">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="saturday">Saturday</h2>
<p>Started today at the brutally early hour of 4 am to catch our tour group’s bus to Auschwitz. When we signed up for the tour, we were supposed to leave at 7:30 am, but the time got bumped up only a couple of days before. This was the first indication that we gotta a bad tour company. We arrived at Auschwitz at 6:30 am and were told we had to wait in line for the free first-come, first-served tickets. Our tour group declined to tell us while booking that we would be waiting in line with everyone instead of getting prebooked passes like the fancier tour groups. The line didn’t start moving until the ticket desk opened at 7:30, and we waited until 10:30 to get our tickets. Luckily, the time passed pretty quickly, playing word games and sharing riddles. Unfortunately, our 10:30 arrival at the ticket desk only guaranteed us tickets for the 4:15 pm time slot. Auschwitz is moving to a digital ticketing system on May 1st (so it should already be in place), meaning we only missed by less than a week. I know I shouldn’t be complaining so much while visiting Auschwitz, but it was frustrating to be told one thing while booking and show up to a completely different experience. After getting our tickets, we took the bus to Birenau for a few hours before coming back for our 4:15 Auschwitz time slot. We didn’t get back to the hostel until almost 9 pm. Thankfully, the hostel had free dinner from 9-10:30, and it was surprisingly good, with a large variety of dishes. Shout-out Greg and Tom! Probably the most mentally taxing day of study abroad yet, but definitely a worthwhile experience.&nbsp;</p>
<div class="cell column-page quarto-layout-panel" data-layout-ncol="2" data-layout-nrow="1">
<div class="quarto-layout-row">
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 50.0%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 13 Krakow/media/waitingline.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>waiting in line to get tickets</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 50.0%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 13 Krakow/media/hosteldinner.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>Surprisingly good free dinner at the hostel</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<section id="birkenau" class="level3 page-columns page-full">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="birkenau">Birkenau</h3>
<p>Walking through Birkenau, one of the most notorious death camps of WWII, on one of the nicest days of the year was a very strange juxtaposition. We entered the camp through Hell’s Gate, where new arrivals to the camp were brought in by train. Most of the camp is ruins after the SS bombed it to erase evidence of their crimes at the end of WWII. We walked through rows upon rows of brick chimneys that used to be attached to wooden barracks that were burned to the ground. The two main gas chamber buildings at the end of the camp were also reduced to rubble. There was a small sign explaining the various chambers in the buildings, but in general, there was limited signage, instead, it was more about taking in the immense scale of the killing that took place. I did at times wish we were part of one of the larger tour groups to get more information at each historical stop. At the end of our circuit around Birkenau, we stepped into a few reconstructed buildings displaying the living situation of prisoners in the camp. Four or more people were crammed into each level of a bunk bed, with 400 people sharing a barracks with only small stoves to serve as heating in the cold winters. Bathroom conditions weren’t any better and Nazi guards made prisoners go to the bathroom in large groups for efficiency. I don’t want to imagine the punishment for having to go to the bathroom out of turn.&nbsp;</p>
<div class="cell column-page quarto-layout-panel" data-layout-ncol="2" data-layout-nrow="3">
<div class="quarto-layout-row">
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 50.0%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 13 Krakow/media/birkenauentrance.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>The entrance building through which men, women, and children were brought by train to Birkenau</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 50.0%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 13 Krakow/media/memorial.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>International Monument to the Victims of Fascism</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="quarto-layout-row">
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 50.0%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 13 Krakow/media/memorial2.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>‘To the memory of the men, women, and children who fell victim to the Nazi genocide. Here lie their ashes. May their souls rest in peace.’ There were many instances of these memorial headstones throughout Birkenau</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 50.0%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 13 Krakow/media/gaschamber.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>Ruins of one of the two major gassing chambers, both were bombed by the SS</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="quarto-layout-row">
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 50.0%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 13 Krakow/media/birkenau.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>Most of Birkenau remains ruins after the SS bombed the death camp during the end of the war to cover up their crimes</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 50.0%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 13 Krakow/media/bunks.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>Recreated bunk rooms show what living situations were like in Birkenau</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="quarto-layout-row">
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 50.0%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 13 Krakow/media/toilets.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>Recreated bathroom buildings show what toilets were like in Birkenau</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</section>
<section id="auschwitz" class="level3 page-columns page-full">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="auschwitz">Auschwitz</h3>
<p>The Auschwitz museum was designed in a way that we couldn’t see the camp from the parking lot, only after entering the museum and walking down a large corridor did we emerge in the camp. Walking through the Arbeit Macht Frei entrance gate was a very surreal experience. The first thing I noticed was how intact all of the buildings in Auschwitz were compared to Birkenau. Almost all of the buildings were dedicated to showing some aspect of the life of the men, women, and children living in the camp. The Auschwitz museum had a very different feel from many holocaust museums in the United States. There was less overall information, and the exhibits focused much more on the prisoners in Auschwitz as opposed to the Nazis and Hitler. I don’t remember seeing a single mention of Hitler in Auschwitz. I think this different style of museum worked very well for Auschwitz because, similar to Birkenau, it’s more about being in the location where so many horrors were experienced. One of the most powerful parts was the images of men and women lining the walls in many of the buildings. Under the images was listed the name, occupation, date of arrival at Auschwitz, and date of death. For almost every person, they passed away less than a year after they arrived. Because of our late arrival time, we only had two hours to experience the museum, we definitely could have spent a couple more hours because we weren’t able to go inside all of the building exhibits.&nbsp;</p>
<div class="cell column-page quarto-layout-panel" data-layout-ncol="2" data-layout-nrow="2">
<div class="quarto-layout-row">
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 50.0%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 13 Krakow/media/entrygate.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>‘Arbeit Macht Frei’ which translates to ‘work makes (one) free’ hangs above one of the main entrances to Auschwitz</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 50.0%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 13 Krakow/media/deathwall.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>Death Wall where numerous camp prisoners were shot</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="quarto-layout-row">
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 50.0%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 13 Krakow/media/guardtower.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>Guard towers were posted frequently around the perimeter making escape nearly impossible</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 50.0%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 13 Krakow/media/betweengates.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>Two walls of barbed wire surround the entirety of Auschwitz</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</section>
</section>
<section id="sunday" class="level2 page-columns page-full">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="sunday">Sunday</h2>
<p>We checked out of the hostel at 10 am after eating the free breakfast, which unfortunately did not live up to the standards of dinner the night before. We were quite late for breakfast, so maybe it was better earlier in the morning before many things ran out. We walked back towards the river, stopping on the way to step inside the Basilica of St.&nbsp;Francis of Assisi. We found a nice grassy area near the castle from Friday to sit and play cards for a couple of hours before grabbing our train back to Prague at 3:30.&nbsp;</p>
<div class="cell column-page quarto-layout-panel" data-layout-ncol="2" data-layout-nrow="2">
<div class="quarto-layout-row">
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 50.0%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 13 Krakow/media/donut.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>Supplimenting breakfast with a pistachio donut</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 50.0%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 13 Krakow/media/basilica.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>Basilica of St.&nbsp;Francis of Assisi</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="quarto-layout-row">
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 50.0%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 13 Krakow/media/kemps.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>Playing Kemps</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 50.0%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 13 Krakow/media/kebab.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>Of course we ended our time in Krakow with a kebab</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>Travel</category>
  <guid>https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 13 Krakow/</guid>
  <pubDate>Tue, 06 May 2025 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 13 Krakow/media/castle2.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>April 30, 2025</title>
  <dc:creator>Ian Beilfuss</dc:creator>
  <link>https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 12 Bratislava and Vienna/</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 




<p>This weekend we traveled to Bratislava and Vienna! We had heard that Vienna was expensive, so we decided to stay in Bratislava Friday and Saturday nights but do a day trip to Vienna because it’s only an hour and a half away. It may have been cheaper, but staying in Vienna at least one, if not both nights would have been much more enjoyable. There’s just so much more to do, especially for nightlife, and taking the bus to and from Vienna was kinda annoying. We decided that we were glad to check Bratislava off the travel list, but that it was a one-and-done destination.</p>
<section id="bratislava-friday" class="level2 page-columns page-full">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="bratislava-friday">Bratislava Friday</h2>
<p>We took the Můj Vlak train to Bratislava from Prague and arrived at 2 pm. It was a nice change of pace to take a train instead of a bus. Technically, we had assigned seats, but we wanted a table to play cards together, so we would pitch up in a spot and then move when someone kicked us out. Bratislava felt like a ghost town. Maybe it was the rainy weather, but there was hardly anyone outside, which felt strange compared to the other cities we visited. We checked into our hostel for the weekend, Patio Hostel. It was nice to have private dorm rooms, but the hostel was pretty lacking; the bathrooms were still shared with the rest of the floor, and it felt like we were the only ones under the age of 40. Maybe Bratislava doesn’t get a lot of young tourists, or maybe we just messed up and picked a hostel that caters to older travelers. But it was cheap and we didn’t have to spend much time there, so I can’t complain.</p>
<div class="cell column-page quarto-layout-panel" data-layout-nrow="1" data-layout-ncol="3">
<div class="quarto-layout-row">
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 33.3%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 12 Bratislava and Vienna/media/group3.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>Arrived in Bratislava</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 33.3%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 12 Bratislava and Vienna/media/map.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>Very cool map of old Bratislava</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 33.3%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 12 Bratislava and Vienna/media/pool.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>Cool water pool</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<section id="ufo-tower" class="level3 page-columns page-full">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="ufo-tower">UFO Tower</h3>
<p>The UFO Tower was our first stop in Bratislava. It was $11 to go up to the observation deck, which felt a bit overpriced, but the view was fantastic. The wind was blowing strongly, but at least it stopped raining. We had a full 360 panorama of Bratislava and the surrounding area. Bratislava looked like it had three distinct areas. An older area which looked more similar to the area around Prague Castle, the downtown with skyscrapers, and the residential area with dozens of copy-paste Soviet-style apartment buildings. It was strange to see skyscrapers after not having any in Prague or Budapest, considering how culturally similar they are. There were a lot of small river cruise ships. I think a cruise down the Danube from Vienna to Budapest, passing through Bratislava and small towns, would be interesting. I liked how much green there was on the west side of the river, and northwest of the city, there were over a hundred wind turbines. The UFO tower is apparently part of the World Federation of Great Towers, joining the Space Needle, Eiffel Tower, Burj Khalifa, Sears Tower, and many more, although it didn’t really feel as worthy of the honor.</p>
<div class="cell column-page quarto-layout-panel" data-layout-nrow="2" data-layout-ncol="2">
<div class="quarto-layout-row">
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 50.0%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 12 Bratislava and Vienna/media/ufo.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>Definately looks like a UFO</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 50.0%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 12 Bratislava and Vienna/media/ufoview1.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>View of Western Bratislava</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="quarto-layout-row">
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 50.0%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 12 Bratislava and Vienna/media/ufoview2.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>View of Eastern Bratislava</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 50.0%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 12 Bratislava and Vienna/media/group1.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>Cold and windy group photo</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</section>
<section id="bratislava-castle" class="level3 page-columns page-full">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="bratislava-castle">Bratislava Castle</h3>
<p>Our second stop of the day was the Bratislava Castle. On the way, we stopped at St.&nbsp;Martin’s Cathedral, which was very large but not as ornate as a lot of the other Cathedrals I’ve visited. It feels blasphemous to say, but I think I prefer Bratislava Castle to Prague Castle, although if I’m including the Cathedral in the center of Prague Castle, then it probably gets the edge. The Castle also had a nice view of the city. We walked around the outside a bit, but the inner courtyard was closed, so we decided to leave and come back on Sunday.</p>
<div class="cell column-page quarto-layout-panel" data-layout-nrow="1" data-layout-ncol="2">
<div class="quarto-layout-row">
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 50.0%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 12 Bratislava and Vienna/media/castle.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>Bratislava Castle</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 50.0%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 12 Bratislava and Vienna/media/castle2.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>Gardens in the back of the castle</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</section>
<section id="dinner" class="level3 page-columns page-full">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="dinner">Dinner</h3>
<p>For dinner, we went to the Slovak Pub, which came highly recommended online. I ordered the potato pierogi, which was fine but not exceptional. They didn’t have the 1L beers like we had been told, and the service wasn’t great, so overall we weren’t too impressed. Maybe we went on a bad night.</p>
<div class="cell quarto-layout-panel page-columns page-full" data-layout-nrow="1" data-layout-ncol="2">
<div class="quarto-layout-row page-full">
<div class="quarto-layout-cell page-columns page-full" style="flex-basis: 50.0%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center page-columns page-full">
<figure class="figure page-columns page-full">
<p class="page-columns page-full"><img src="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 12 Bratislava and Vienna/media/bratislavadinner.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img column-page"></p>
<figcaption>Dinner at the Slovak Pub</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</section>
</section>
<section id="vienna-saturday" class="level2 page-columns page-full">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="vienna-saturday">Vienna Saturday</h2>
<p>We took the RegioJet bus to Vienna at 7:30 am this morning. We beelined for breakfast first. All of the cafes that were recommended to us had huge lines, but we ended up at a place called Stadtcafe, and I got a delicious breakfast sandwich. First stops after that were St Peter’s Cathedral and the Sisi Museum. The architecture of Vienna is amazing! Behind the Museum was a huge open area with a lot of museums. There were some people playing spikeball, so of course Peter and I asked to join for a game. They had cleats and Spikeball jerseys, and we got destroyed, but it was a blast. I love how Vienna has public water filling locations scattered around the city; more places in Europe need to do this!</p>
<div class="cell column-page quarto-layout-panel" data-layout-nrow="3" data-layout-ncol="3">
<div class="quarto-layout-row">
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 33.3%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 12 Bratislava and Vienna/media/viennabreakfast.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>Breakfast</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 33.3%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 12 Bratislava and Vienna/media/stpeters.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>St Peter’s</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 33.3%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 12 Bratislava and Vienna/media/stpetersinside.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>Inside St.&nbsp;Peter’s</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="quarto-layout-row">
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 33.3%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 12 Bratislava and Vienna/media/stpetersorgan.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>The St.&nbsp;Peter’s organ</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 33.3%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 12 Bratislava and Vienna/media/sisi.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>Sisi Museum</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 33.3%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 12 Bratislava and Vienna/media/eugene.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>Prince Eugene Monument</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="quarto-layout-row">
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 33.3%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 12 Bratislava and Vienna/media/spikeball.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>Spikeball!</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<section id="st-stephens" class="level3 page-columns page-full">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="st-stephens">St Stephen’s</h3>
<p>St.&nbsp;Stephen’s is definitely the flagship of Vienna. I loved the Gothic architecture style, with so much intricate detail. The interior was huge with lots of amazing stone carvings. We wanted to go up into one of the towers, but the admission fee was cash only, and not everyone had enough.</p>
<div class="cell column-page quarto-layout-panel" data-layout-nrow="1" data-layout-ncol="2">
<div class="quarto-layout-row">
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 50.0%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 12 Bratislava and Vienna/media/ststephens.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>St Stephen’s Cathedral</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 50.0%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 12 Bratislava and Vienna/media/ststephensinside.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>Inside</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</section>
<section id="belvedere" class="level3 page-columns page-full">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="belvedere">Belvedere</h3>
<p>I loved the Belevdere Palace! Really beautiful gardens to walk through and enjoy. The view across the reservoir to the Palace was amazing. Unfortunately, the museum was sold out of tickets for the day so I’ll have to come back another time.</p>
<div class="cell column-page quarto-layout-panel" data-layout-nrow="1" data-layout-ncol="3">
<div class="quarto-layout-row">
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 33.3%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 12 Bratislava and Vienna/media/belvedere.jpg" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>Belvedere</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 33.3%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 12 Bratislava and Vienna/media/belvedere1.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>Lower Belvedere</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 33.3%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 12 Bratislava and Vienna/media/group2.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>Group pic</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</section>
<section id="hundertwasser-house" class="level3 page-columns page-full">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="hundertwasser-house">Hundertwasser House</h3>
<p>I don’t think I’ve ever seen anything quite like the Hundertwasser House. The architectural style felt a bit like a post-apocalyptic apartment complex. I’m curious if anyone actually lives in the apartments or if it’s mainly just a tourist attraction. There was a large gift shop building too, I was so tempted to get one of the matted paintings, but $50 was a bit more than I wanted to spend.</p>
<div class="cell column-page quarto-layout-panel" data-layout-nrow="1" data-layout-ncol="2">
<div class="quarto-layout-row">
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 50.0%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 12 Bratislava and Vienna/media/hundertwasser1.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>St Stephen’s Cathedral</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 50.0%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 12 Bratislava and Vienna/media/hundertwasser2.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>Inside</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</section>
<section id="dinner-1" class="level3 page-columns page-full">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="dinner-1">Dinner</h3>
<p>For whatever reason, we decided to trust Tristan with finding a place for dinner. He made a reservation for Chez Bernard, which was quite a bit fancier than we were used to. The restaurant was on the 7th floor of a nice hotel. The meal was $45 a person for a main dish and a beer. The food was very good, but I was definitely not ready to be paying so much for it. The restaurant also added a $5 per person place setting charge, which apparently is common for upscale Austrian restaurants, but I had never seen that before.</p>
<div class="cell quarto-layout-panel page-columns page-full" data-layout-nrow="1" data-layout-ncol="2">
<div class="quarto-layout-row page-full">
<div class="quarto-layout-cell page-columns page-full" style="flex-basis: 50.0%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center page-columns page-full">
<figure class="figure page-columns page-full">
<p class="page-columns page-full"><img src="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 12 Bratislava and Vienna/media/viennadinner.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img column-page"></p>
<figcaption>Chicken and austrian gnocci</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</section>
<section id="fitzcarraldo-speakeasy" class="level3 page-columns page-full">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="fitzcarraldo-speakeasy">Fitzcarraldo Speakeasy</h3>
<p>After dinner, we headed to a speakeasy that Tristan was obsessed with finding. To get in, we had to press a button on a vending machine, and the speakeasy was hidden behind it. The place was very small and dim, but the atmosphere was perfect. All the tables were reserved, but they had space for us to stand at the bar, which turned out to be much more fun because we could watch the bartenders make the fancy drinks. Rafe and I ordered the Elyx Gimlet, which came on top of a rock holder with a light underneath. The drink started bright purple, but then the bartender poured in something that turned the whole drink neon green. Peter and Violette ordered a drink that came with a foot-tall tower of bubbles that they had to eat before getting to the actual drink. Paying $18 after spending so much on dinner was not great, but for the experience, it was worth it.</p>
<div class="cell column-page quarto-layout-panel" data-layout-nrow="2" data-layout-ncol="3">
<div class="quarto-layout-row">
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 33.3%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 12 Bratislava and Vienna/media/speakeasydoor.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>Vending machine entrance</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 33.3%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 12 Bratislava and Vienna/media/speakeasy.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>Inside the speakeasy</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 33.3%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 12 Bratislava and Vienna/media/drink.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>My neon green drink</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="quarto-layout-row">
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 33.3%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><video src="media/drinkvid.mp4" class="img-fluid" controls=""><a href="media/drinkvid.mp4">Video</a></video></p>
<figcaption>So cool to watch them make it</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 33.3%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><video src="media/peterdrink.mp4" class="img-fluid" controls=""><a href="media/peterdrink.mp4">Video</a></video></p>
<figcaption>Peter had fun with this one</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</section>
</section>
<section id="bratislava-sunday" class="level2 page-columns page-full">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="bratislava-sunday">Bratislava Sunday</h2>
<div class="cell column-page quarto-layout-panel" data-layout-nrow="1" data-layout-ncol="2">
<div class="quarto-layout-row">
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 50.0%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 12 Bratislava and Vienna/media/spoons.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>Playing spoons outside of Bratislava Castle</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 50.0%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 12 Bratislava and Vienna/media/fountain.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>Found this cool fountain on our walk to the train station</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<section id="blue-church" class="level3 page-columns page-full">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="blue-church">Blue Church</h3>
<p>The Blue Church did indeed live up to its name; the whole exterior was baby blue, and the interior had a lot of blue accents as well. There was an Easter service happening, so we could only peek inside.</p>
<div class="cell column-page quarto-layout-panel" data-layout-nrow="1" data-layout-ncol="2">
<div class="quarto-layout-row">
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 50.0%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 12 Bratislava and Vienna/media/bluechurch.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>Blue Church</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 50.0%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 12 Bratislava and Vienna/media/bluechurchinside.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>Inside Blue Church</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</section>
<section id="medieval-market" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="medieval-market">Medieval Market</h3>
<p>We made it back to Bratislava Castle for the medieval market. Unfortunately, I didn’t take any pictures, but the market was great. There were like 15 stalls with people dressed in medieval attire selling handmade pottery, wooden bowls, knives, necklaces, and many other things. They also had a few food stands which I didn’t try but looks pretty good.</p>
</section>
</section>
<section id="prague-easter" class="level2 page-columns page-full">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="prague-easter">Prague Easter</h2>
<section id="markets" class="level3 page-columns page-full">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="markets">Markets</h3>
<p>We had the day off from school for Easter Monday, so we headed into the city to go to the Easter Markets. The markets had been up for a couple of weeks, but this was my first time going. We visited the markets in Old Town Square and Wenceslas Square. They sold very similar stuff, lots of kielbasa, shish kebabs, jewelry, and hot wine, but it was great to hang out on such a beautiful day. I did find a stand selling small drawings of popular Prague landmarks, I purchased one of Old Town Square that I really liked.</p>
<div class="cell column-page quarto-layout-panel" data-layout-nrow="1" data-layout-ncol="2">
<div class="quarto-layout-row">
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 50.0%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 12 Bratislava and Vienna/media/market.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>Easter Market in Old Town Square</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 50.0%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 12 Bratislava and Vienna/media/tulips.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>Beautiful tulips with St.&nbsp;Nicholar Church in the background</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</section>
<section id="whipping-tradition" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="whipping-tradition">Whipping Tradition</h3>
<p>One of the most unique and interesting Easter traditions in Czechia is the whipping tradition. On Easter Monday, Czech boys collect willow branches and braid them together to create a whip. They decorate the whip with ribbons and then whip girls. The whipping is supposed to bring the girls good luck and fertility. Predecorated whips were being sold at all of the Easter Markets and even on campus. From what I saw, the tradition isn’t really done anymore in Prague; the selling of whips is more just honoring the history of the tradition at this point.</p>


</section>
</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>Czechia</category>
  <category>Travel</category>
  <guid>https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 12 Bratislava and Vienna/</guid>
  <pubDate>Wed, 30 Apr 2025 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 12 Bratislava and Vienna/media/cover.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>April 21, 2025</title>
  <dc:creator>Ian Beilfuss</dc:creator>
  <link>https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 11 Mallorca/</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 




<section id="thursday" class="level2 page-columns page-full">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="thursday">Thursday</h2>
<p>Today was a long day of travel. Our plane left Prague at 11 a.m., and we got to the airport a bit early, so we had some fun playing FIFA on the free PS5s they have at the AC Sparta store. Unfortunately, we got stuck with a three-hour layover in Vienna because Austrian Airlines was the cheapest flight. Fortunately, the Vienna airport had free foosball and Nintendo to kill some time. Our flight to Mallorca arrived at around 6 pm, and Amelia’s friend Jade and her friend Raff picked us up from the airport. We had initially tried to find a way to make our Mallorca trip work without having to rent cars, but our Airbnb was far from Palma, and the public transport on the island isn’t very good. Having cars to visit more beaches and to be able to see more of the Island was totally worth it. Plus, the car rentals only turned out to be $45 per person for the four days we were there, which seemed like a great deal. We arrived at the Airbnb an hour later, and it was incredible! Beautiful little four-bedroom, eight-bed house in a small town, only a ten-minute walk from the ocean. The house had a pool, but it was never warm enough to swim comfortably. Shout out to Carmen for being a great Airbnb host and for being willing to take her chance on renting to us even though we were well under her age minimum of 30 (for the record, we were very good guests). For sunset, we walked down to the local beach, Cala S’Amarador. Unfortunately, it was cloudy and windy, but it still felt amazing to be on the ocean.</p>
<div class="cell column-page quarto-layout-panel" data-layout-ncol="3" data-layout-nrow="1">
<div class="quarto-layout-row">
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 33.3%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 11 Mallorca/media/PS5.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>Playing FIFA was a great way to kill time before our flight</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 33.3%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 11 Mallorca/media/foos.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>Free foosball at the Vienna Airport</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 33.3%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 11 Mallorca/media/nintendo.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>Free Nintendos also</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="quarto-layout-row">
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 33.3%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 11 Mallorca/media/house.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>Airbnb for the trio</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 33.3%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 11 Mallorca/media/pool.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>Regrettably we did not take advantage of the pool</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 33.3%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 11 Mallorca/media/arrival.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>Greetings from Mallorca!</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="quarto-layout-row">
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 33.3%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 11 Mallorca/media/closebeach.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>Cala S’Amarador</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 33.3%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 11 Mallorca/media/sandwich.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>Made an enormous sandwich for lunch tomorrow</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</section>
<section id="friday" class="level2 page-columns page-full">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="friday">Friday</h2>
<p>Big day of beach hopping!</p>
<section id="caló-des-moro" class="level3 page-columns page-full">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="caló-des-moro">Caló des Moro</h3>
<p>Unfortunately, one of our rental cars got rear-ended on the way to the beach, but thankfully, we had paid for full insurance coverage, and only the license plate was damaged. Caló des Moro was gorgeous! The water was crystal clear, and cliffs jutted out into the ocean. Reminded me a bit of Pictured Rocks National Lakeshore in the Upper Peninsula. There were people cliff jumping on the other side of the beach, so naturally we had to join in. The cliff was only like ten feet above the water, but it was such a blast. We only went in twice, though, because it was cold and windy when we got out. Honestly, the water felt warmer than the air. We still ended up hanging out for a long while and even ate lunch there. After we walked around one of the cliffs to another beautiful beach. The whole area was managed by a local family, which I think is great.</p>
<div class="cell column-page quarto-layout-panel" data-layout-ncol="2" data-layout-nrow="1">
<div class="quarto-layout-row">
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 50.0%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 11 Mallorca/media/cliffsbeach.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>Mallorca is stunning!</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 50.0%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 11 Mallorca/media/jump.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>Cliff jumping!</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="quarto-layout-row">
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 50.0%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 11 Mallorca/media/group.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>The Mallorca group</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 50.0%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 11 Mallorca/media/calodesmoro.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>Caló des Moro</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</section>
<section id="el-caragol" class="level3 page-columns page-full">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="el-caragol">El Caragol</h3>
<p>This beach was a bit of a nightmare to get to. Google Maps had no idea that the route it wanted us to take involved private, gated-off roads. It took us a lot of tries to figure out where to go. At one point, we found ourselves on a narrow one-lane dirt road that abruptly dead-ended. We had to do a 25-point turn to get back on track. Half an hour later, we finally made it to the beach. It was a half-mile walk along the coast to the beach from the parking lot. Cabrera Island was visible in the distance the whole time. It would be interesting to visit at some point since I think it’s all a national park. We didn’t actually make it to the beach because we found a fun rock outcropping with some old stone structures to explore. And no one was in the mood to swim with the cool weather and wind.</p>
<div class="cell column-page quarto-layout-panel" data-layout-ncol="3" data-layout-nrow="1">
<div class="quarto-layout-row">
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 33.3%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 11 Mallorca/media/carjam.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>Got ourselves into a bit of a jam</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 33.3%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 11 Mallorca/media/elcaragol.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>Cabrera Island in the distance</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 33.3%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 11 Mallorca/media/wheel.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>A strange sight on the beach</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</section>
<section id="es-pontàs-and-cala-santanyi" class="level3 page-columns page-full">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="es-pontàs-and-cala-santanyi">Es Pontàs and Cala Santanyi</h3>
<p>I loved the Es Pontàs arch! Such a cool natural formation, I was surprised it wasn’t more crowded at the lookout point. Cala Sanranyi was the most touristy of the beaches we visited today. There were a lot of hotels built right next to it. Luckily, it wasn’t crowded. We lay out on towels for an hour until it got too cold. The only person swimming was a small kid who was having fun trying to jump over the waves.</p>
<div class="cell column-page quarto-layout-panel" data-layout-ncol="2" data-layout-nrow="1">
<div class="quarto-layout-row">
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 50.0%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 11 Mallorca/media/arch.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>Es Pontàs</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 50.0%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 11 Mallorca/media/peter.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>Arch pic with Peter</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</section>
<section id="cooking" class="level3 page-columns page-full">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="cooking">Cooking</h3>
<p>Forgot how much I missed cooking in a proper kitchen! It even had a gas stove! We made tacos that turned out really well. Group dinner was a success!</p>
<div class="cell column-page quarto-layout-panel" data-layout-ncol="2" data-layout-nrow="1">
<div class="quarto-layout-row">
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 50.0%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 11 Mallorca/media/tacos.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>Group tacos</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 50.0%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 11 Mallorca/media/tacos1.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>Not bad for an Airbnb meal</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</section>
</section>
<section id="saturday" class="level2 page-columns page-full">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="saturday">Saturday</h2>
<section id="boat-cruise" class="level3 page-columns page-full">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="boat-cruise">Boat cruise</h3>
<p>Most of today was spent on a boat cruise through Magic Catamarans! It was fantastic to spend so much time on the water, but it was very cold. The weather was overcast most of the day, and there was a lot of wind on the boat. We hung out in mesh at the front of the boat the whole time. They offered snorkeling equipment, which we were stoked about before the cruise, but after getting whipped around by the cold wind, no one was excited about jumping in the water, and there wasn’t anything to see underwater either. We were served a decent lunch with a kebab, chicken breast, brat, and salad. They also gave out glasses of sangria, which helped take the chill off. Warmer weather and sun would have made it a better experience, but we still had a great time, hard to complain when you’re on the Mediterranean.</p>
<div class="cell column-page quarto-layout-panel" data-layout-ncol="2" data-layout-nrow="1">
<div class="quarto-layout-row">
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 50.0%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 11 Mallorca/media/otherboat.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>Catamaran!</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 50.0%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 11 Mallorca/media/groupboat.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>Everyone on the boat</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="quarto-layout-row">
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 50.0%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 11 Mallorca/media/coldboat.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>Loved laying on the netting but it was chilly</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 50.0%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 11 Mallorca/media/boatlunch.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>Boat lunch</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</section>
<section id="palma" class="level3 page-columns page-full">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="palma">Palma</h3>
<p>We finished the cruise at around 3 and headed into the Palma city center. We got our souvenir shopping out of the way and visited Palma Cathedral. We weren’t able to go inside, but the architecture was stunning! Love the gothic style. We walked around the area a bit more and randomly stumbled on a rock festival, which was entertaining. From our brief visit, I really liked Palma, especially all the narrow alleys lined with shops.</p>
<div class="cell column-page quarto-layout-panel" data-layout-ncol="3" data-layout-nrow="1">
<div class="quarto-layout-row">
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 33.3%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 11 Mallorca/media/street.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>Loved the trees lining this street</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 33.3%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 11 Mallorca/media/cathedral.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>Palma Cathedral</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 33.3%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 11 Mallorca/media/cathedral3.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>Love the architecture of the Cathedral</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</section>
<section id="sóller" class="level3 page-columns page-full">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="sóller">Sóller</h3>
<p>After Palma, we drove for an hour to the small town of Sóller. The road there passed through the longest tunnel I’ve ever been in; it must have taken at least 5 minutes to go through. I attempted to hold my breath, but quickly realized it was futile. Sóller was a very pretty little town nestled in the mountains. We parked and walked to the main square, where there was a traditional dance happening. There were maybe 50 people of all ages dancing in unison. We watched for at least 15 minutes, it would have been fun to be able to learn how to do it; they were all very good. The town square was also home to the Parroquia de Sant Bartomeu de Sóller. The architectural style felt very similar to Palma Cathedral, very pretty! Unfortunately, the restaurant we wanted to go to for tapas was fully booked, so we ended up at a place a few minutes from the main square. I ordered the beef cheek tacos. They were good, but nothing amazing. I would have rather had our homemade tacos from last night again.</p>
<div class="cell column-page quarto-layout-panel" data-layout-ncol="3" data-layout-nrow="1">
<div class="quarto-layout-row">
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 33.3%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 11 Mallorca/media/cathedral2.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>Parroquia de Sant Bartomeu de Sóller</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 33.3%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 11 Mallorca/media/dance.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>Traditional dancing in the town square</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 33.3%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 11 Mallorca/media/tacos2.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>Beef cheek tacos</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>


</section>
</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>Travel</category>
  <guid>https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 11 Mallorca/</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 21 Apr 2025 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 11 Mallorca/media/calodesmoro.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>April 15, 2025</title>
  <dc:creator>Ian Beilfuss</dc:creator>
  <link>https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 10 Ireland/</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 




<section id="cork" class="level2 page-columns page-full">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="cork">Cork</h2>
<p>This was my third time visiting Cork, although I was too young to remember the first time, and the second time was just driving through. My main purpose for coming to Cork was to visit my grandmother, Breda! She grew up in the area and moved back full-time about a decade ago. Only staying one night was far too short of a visit with her but I was still glad to be able to visit. She lives in a cute little house near Ballincollig, about a half-hour drive from Cork city center. It was really nice to be able to sleep somewhere that wasn’t a hostel dorm room! I didn’t arrive in Cork until the late afternoon on Thursday so we didn’t really have time to sightseeing so we made the most of it on Friday. Started off on Friday with a Hop-on Hop-off bus. Normally I would never think of touring a city like this but it was actually pretty great. I got to see a lot of the Cork highlights in only an hour and a half. I think my favorite site was the Shandon Clock Tower, which the tour guide said was the largest 4-faced clock tower until Big Ben was built. When the tower was originally built the clock hands were made of wood and the locals called it the “Four-Faced Liar” because the hands would get blown in the wind and all tell a different time. After the bus tour, we walked around the University College Cork campus. Loved this campus, the original campus building was a beautiful old castle-looking building with a lot of nice green space. Next, we headed back to St.&nbsp;Patrick’s St, the central hub of Cork that traverses the Cork island. Breda grew up in the area and spent a lot of her life in Cork so she knew the history of almost every building and how it had changed in the last century! We spent the afternoon walking around Cork’s churches and cathedrals, including Saint Fin Barre’s Cathedral, St Peter’s, and the Irish Franciscans Church. Although we didn’t go inside, Saint Fin Barre’s Cathedral was one of my favorite cathedrals architecturally that I’ve seen in Europe.</p>
<div class="cell column-page quarto-layout-panel" data-layout-ncol="3" data-layout-nrow="1">
<div class="quarto-layout-row">
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 33.3%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 10 Ireland/media/breda.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>Breda!</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 33.3%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 10 Ireland/media/tree.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>I climbed this tree when I was 3, unfotunately it isn’t doing so well now</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 33.3%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 10 Ireland/media/bus.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>On the hop-on hop-off bus</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="quarto-layout-row">
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 33.3%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 10 Ireland/media/barre2.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>Saint Fin Barre’s Cathedral</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 33.3%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 10 Ireland/media/peters.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>Inside St Peter’s</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 33.3%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 10 Ireland/media/Franciscans.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>Inside Irish Franciscans Church</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="quarto-layout-row">
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 33.3%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 10 Ireland/media/ucc1.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>The original UCC building is amazing, I would love to take a class there</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 33.3%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 10 Ireland/media/ucc2.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>Lots of nice green space on the UCC campus</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 33.3%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 10 Ireland/media/coatofarms.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>Cork Coat of Arms, love this</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="quarto-layout-row">
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 33.3%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 10 Ireland/media/clock.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>Shandon Clock Tower</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</section>
<section id="dublin" class="level2 page-columns page-full">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="dublin">Dublin</h2>
<section id="guinness-storehouse" class="level3 page-columns page-full">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="guinness-storehouse">Guinness Storehouse</h3>
<p>Despite probably being the number one tourist attraction in Dublin I loved the Guinness Storehouse. For only 30 euros to visit the whole building with a free Guinness sample and pint it seemed like a pretty decent deal too. The whole storehouse is totally over the top with large exhibits dedicated to the ingredients, brewing process, advertising, and legacy of Guinness. I learned a surprising amount about the brewing of Guinness and loved the section about the advertising schemes, there were so many random goofy posters with animals. “Lovely day for a Guinness!”. The tour ended at the top of the Storehouse with fantastic views of Dublin. I definitely gained a new appreciation for Guinness as a company and am now a certified Guinness enjoyer!</p>
<div class="cell column-page quarto-layout-panel" data-layout-ncol="3" data-layout-nrow="1">
<div class="quarto-layout-row">
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 33.3%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 10 Ireland/media/storehouse.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>Crazy water display, the glasses are just made up of falling water droplets</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 33.3%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 10 Ireland/media/yeastmegafan.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>Not sure how one becomes a yeast mega fan but I’m all for it</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 33.3%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 10 Ireland/media/carson.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>Enjoying a free Guinness at the end of the tour, once again I failed to split the G</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="quarto-layout-row">
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 33.3%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 10 Ireland/media/croc.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>Goofy advertising</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 33.3%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 10 Ireland/media/fish.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>A woman needs a man like a fish needs a bicycle</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</section>
<section id="st-patricks-cathedral" class="level3 page-columns page-full">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="st-patricks-cathedral">St Patrick’s Cathedral</h3>
<p>Carson and I spent a solid hour and a half in St Patrick’s Cathedral, the National Cathedral of Ireland. There was a 10 euro admission fee but an audio tour of the Cathedral was included. The audio tour shared a lot of really interesting history of the Cathedral. My favorite part was all the old flags hung up to commemorate Irish soldiers and the Knights of St Patrick’s. There was also a lot of really great stained glass, I think the Irish churches have the most beautiful stained glass of anywhere I’ve been. Entertainingly the Cathedral probably wouldn’t be around today if it wasn’t for the 1860-1865 restoration funded by the Guinness family for the equivalent of 22 million euro today. Carson and I were joking that it seems like everything in Dublin is connected to Guinness somehow.</p>
<div class="cell column-page quarto-layout-panel" data-layout-ncol="3" data-layout-nrow="2">
<div class="quarto-layout-row">
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 33.3%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 10 Ireland/media/patricks.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>St Patrick’s Cathedral</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 33.3%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 10 Ireland/media/patricksknight.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>St Patrick’s Knights, I love these old flags</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 33.3%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 10 Ireland/media/patrickstained.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>Beautiful stained glass</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="quarto-layout-row">
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 33.3%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 10 Ireland/media/spiralsteps.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>Super cool spiral staircase to the organ</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 33.3%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 10 Ireland/media/restoration.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>I swear everything in Dublin is connected to Guinness somehow</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</section>
<section id="other" class="level3 page-columns page-full">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="other">Other</h3>
<section id="abbey-court-hostel" class="level4">
<h4 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="abbey-court-hostel">Abbey Court Hostel</h4>
<p>In Dublin, we stayed at the Abbey Court Hostel, definitely the strangest hostel I’ve been in yet. Every wall was covered in artwork and the place was a total maze, to get to our dorm room we had to walk through part of the women’s bathroom. It was $70 per night for a six-bed dorm room which was the cheapest we could find in Dublin, seems so crazy expensive compared to the $20-30 per night I’ve paid in other cities. The price did include free breakfast, although it was shitty, and a game room with foosball, table tennis, and pool which we had fun in.</p>
</section>
<section id="gardens-at-the-royal-hospital-kilmainham" class="level4">
<h4 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="gardens-at-the-royal-hospital-kilmainham">Gardens at the Royal Hospital Kilmainham</h4>
<p>We arrived a half hour early for our Guinness Storehouse tour so to kill some time we wandered over to a nearby park which ended up being great. The gardens at the Royal Hospital Kilmainham felt like something straight out of Game of Thrones with all the manicured hedges. We found a fun little bird that wanted to pose for a picture too.</p>
</section>
<section id="national-gallery-of-ireland" class="level4 page-columns page-full">
<h4 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="national-gallery-of-ireland">National Gallery of Ireland</h4>
<p>On Sunday morning we had an hour to kill between the hostel check-out and when I had to take the bus to the airport so we decided to check out the National Gallery. Amazingly the Gallery is free for anyone and has a lot of really amazing art. I loved all the landscape paintings. I would highly recommend spending some time there if you have some time to kill in Dublin.</p>
<div class="cell column-page quarto-layout-panel" data-layout-ncol="3" data-layout-nrow="1">
<div class="quarto-layout-row">
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 33.3%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 10 Ireland/media/hostel.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>The hostel walls were covered in artwork</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 33.3%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 10 Ireland/media/foosball.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>Foosball!</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 33.3%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 10 Ireland/media/dublincastle.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>Dublin Castle</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="quarto-layout-row">
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 33.3%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 10 Ireland/media/garden.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>Gardens at the Royal Hospital Kilmainham</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 33.3%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 10 Ireland/media/bird.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>Little bird was posing</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 33.3%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 10 Ireland/media/painting.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>One of my favorite paintings from the National Gallery</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</section>
</section>
</section>
<section id="food" class="level2 page-columns page-full">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="food">Food</h2>
<p>My favorite meal in Cork was at a quaint little restaurant called Scoozi. I got a prosciutto and arugula pizza that was tasty. The first night in Dublin Carson and I went to a delicious noodles place called Lee’s Charming Noodles, unfortunately, I didn’t get a picture. For lunch on Sunday we got poke bowls which might actually be the healthier meals I’ve had yet, and it tasted great. For dinner on Saturday we went to White Rabbit. The restaurant was hidden in the back of a convenience store but totally worth it, I got the chicken cup bop and loved it.</p>
<div class="cell column-page quarto-layout-panel" data-layout-ncol="3" data-layout-nrow="1">
<div class="quarto-layout-row">
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 33.3%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 10 Ireland/media/pizza.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>Pizza from Scoozi!</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 33.3%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 10 Ireland/media/poke.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>Poke from Nutbutter</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 33.3%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 10 Ireland/media/chickencupbap.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>Chicken cupbap from White Rabbit</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>Travel</category>
  <guid>https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 10 Ireland/</guid>
  <pubDate>Tue, 15 Apr 2025 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 10 Ireland/media/ucc1.JPG" medium="image"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>April 2, 2025</title>
  <dc:creator>Ian Beilfuss</dc:creator>
  <link>https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 9 Rome/</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 




<section id="the-highlights" class="level2 page-columns page-full">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="the-highlights">The Highlights</h2>
<p>This weekend I flew to Rome for a far too brief trip to visit my friends from UW who came to visit for spring break. I was only in Rome for a little bit more than a day and a half but I’d say I made the most of it. Rome has by far the most highlights of European cities I’ve been to so far. So many iconic ruins to visit. That being said, I don’t think I could ever live there, too many people and it’s not the cleanest city.&nbsp;</p>
<section id="colosseum" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="colosseum">Colosseum</h3>
<p>This was my second time at the Colosseum and it was as entrancing as the first time. It’s amazing how well it’s stood the test of time, shout out Roman concrete. It was significantly more crowded than it was last time in 2021 at the tail end of the pandemic. I wish I had been able to go inside but I ran out of time to make it happen on this trip. My friends went inside on Monday after I had left and got their photo taken by Bo Nix, the quarterback for the Denver Broncos… small flex.&nbsp;</p>
</section>
<section id="pantheon" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="pantheon">Pantheon</h3>
<p>We all agreed that this was the highlight of our time in Rome. I missed seeing the Pantheon last time I was in Rome and I’m super glad I got to see it this time. We were waiting in the long line to get in when we were approached by some tour guides who promised to get us in instantly and give us a private guided experience for only $10 ($15 total) more than regular admission. After some debating, we decided to go for it. Best decision! We probably avoided waiting in line for an extra hour and our tour guide was great, look up Jessica Coppola (<a href="mailto:jessicacoppola8@gmail.com">jessicacoppola8@gmail.com</a>) if you’re ever in Rome. It was fascinating to learn about how much effort went into building the Pantheon, from the many types of marble mined from all over the Roman Empire to the rolling of the pillars for hundreds of miles from mine to the final destination. Also shout out to Pope Boniface IV for saving the Pantheon from destruction when he restored it to use as his private place of worship. The Pantheon definitely cracks the top 3 coolest buildings I’ve seen in Europe.&nbsp;</p>
</section>
<section id="monument-of-vittorio-emanuele-ii" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="monument-of-vittorio-emanuele-ii">Monument of Vittorio Emanuele II</h3>
<p>Really big fan of this monument, especially because it was free to go up and in. The views from the top of Rome were fantastic! Hard to imagine the amount of effort that went into lifting the 50 equestrian statue of Victor Emmanuel II into place on its pedestal.&nbsp;</p>
</section>
<section id="trajans-forum" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="trajans-forum">Trajan’s Forum</h3>
<p>Not much to say about Trajan’s Forum, we found our there on the first night while wandering. Lots of cool old pillar ruins. Ancient ruins are so amazing.&nbsp;</p>
</section>
<section id="piazza-navona" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="piazza-navona">Piazza Navona</h3>
<p>Sant’Agnese in Agone Fountain in the center of the square was pretty but pales in comparison to the Trevi Fountain. I really liked the church next to the square, Sant’Agnese in Agone. The stone carvings inside depicting the evil doings of pagans were incredible, my favorite carvings of the trip.&nbsp;</p>
</section>
<section id="trevi-fountain" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="trevi-fountain">Trevi Fountain</h3>
<p>The Trevi Fountain was as beautiful as the last time I saw it, although with way bigger crowds this time. It felt like we were in a club, constantly pushing our way through people. I did really like being able to go to the lower level right next to the fountain to take pictures.&nbsp;</p>
</section>
<section id="spanish-steps" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="spanish-steps">Spanish Steps</h3>
<p>The Spanish Steps were fine but overrated in my opinion, they’re just too crowded. Watching the Italian police constantly tell people not to sit down on the steps was very entertaining. I will say the view from the top of the steps was very pretty.&nbsp;</p>
</section>
<section id="pictures" class="level3 page-columns page-full">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="pictures">Pictures</h3>
<div class="cell column-page quarto-layout-panel" data-layout-ncol="4" data-layout-nrow="4">
<div class="quarto-layout-row">
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 25.0%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 9 Rome/media/river.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>Tiber River by night</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 25.0%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 9 Rome/media/Colosseum.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>The Colosseum!</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 25.0%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 9 Rome/media/grouppic.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>The boys in front of the Colosseum</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 25.0%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 9 Rome/media/Pantheon.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>The Pantheon is so imposing from the outside</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="quarto-layout-row">
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 25.0%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 9 Rome/media/Pantheoninterior.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>So many different types of marble inside the Patheon. Kinda wish it had been raining to see the rain column come down the center</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 25.0%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 9 Rome/media/vittorio.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>Monument of Vittorio Emanuele II</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 25.0%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 9 Rome/media/vittoriostatue.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>50 ton statue!</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 25.0%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 9 Rome/media/street.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>The view from the top of the Monument</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="quarto-layout-row">
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 25.0%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 9 Rome/media/Trajan's Forum.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>Trajan’s Forum</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 25.0%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 9 Rome/media/Temple of Venus Genetrix.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>Temple of Venus Genetrix</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 25.0%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 9 Rome/media/Piazza Navona.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>Nice fountain in the center of Piazza Navona</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 25.0%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 9 Rome/media/Sant'Agnese in Agone.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>Inside Sant’Agnese in Agone, stunning!</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="quarto-layout-row">
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 25.0%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 9 Rome/media/spanishsteps.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>Spanish Steps</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 25.0%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 9 Rome/media/trevi1.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>Trevi Fountain!</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</section>
</section>
<section id="food" class="level2 page-columns page-full">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="food">Food</h2>
<p>As expected, I ate lots of pizza and pasta this weekend! Saturday night, we ate dinner in a cute restaurant called Hostaria al Boschetto. I ordered the fusilli with bacon, mushrooms, rocket, and cheese. I forgot how much I had missed fresh pasta. I definitely need to make some this summer! On Sunday we got lunch at Bona Pizza. The place was packed but counter service was quick, they had a bunch of premade slices to go. I got a delicious pepperoni slice and a weird potato and bacon slice that I ordered on accident but was still pretty good. I’m still taking the Innsbruck as the best pizza I’ve had while abroad though. Also on Sunday, we splurged for some gelato. I got vanilla and two different chocolate flavors. So delicious!</p>
<div class="cell column-page quarto-layout-panel" data-layout-ncol="3" data-layout-nrow="1">
<div class="quarto-layout-row">
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 33.3%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 9 Rome/media/pasta.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>Hostaria al Boschetto</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 33.3%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 9 Rome/media/pizza.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>Bona Pizza</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 33.3%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 9 Rome/media/gelato.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>Gelato</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</section>
<section id="other-fun-stuff" class="level2 page-columns page-full">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="other-fun-stuff">Other Fun Stuff</h2>
<section id="flights" class="level3 page-columns page-full">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="flights">Flights</h3>
<p>This was my first time flying on Wizz Air and Ryan Air. The advertisement in the Wizz Air backseat magazine for becoming a pilot in two years was a bit scary to see before takeoff but both flights went off without a hitch. I really like boarding and deboarding from the front and the back of the plane, it makes everything so much more efficient. I wish more airlines in the US would do the same.</p>
<div class="cell column-page quarto-layout-panel" data-layout-ncol="4" data-layout-nrow="1">
<div class="quarto-layout-row">
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 25.0%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 9 Rome/media/wizzair.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>Boarding for Wizz Air</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 25.0%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 9 Rome/media/wizzair1.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>2 year pilot program…</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 25.0%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 9 Rome/media/ryanair.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>Boarding for Ryanair</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</section>
<section id="italian-police-escort" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="italian-police-escort">Italian Police Escort</h3>
<p>This was possibly the weirdest experience I’ve had abroad yet. We all had to go to the bathroom near the Monument of Vittorio Emanuele II. There was a group of Italian Police standing near where we were so we went up and asked for directions to the bathroom. I’m not sure if something was lost in translation or if they were just bored but we ended up getting escorted by one of the officers to the bathroom. He stopped traffic for us and had us walk down the middle of the road, it was so surreal. I wish we had gotten a picture with the officer but we were all too focused on getting to the bathroom.</p>
</section>
<section id="souvenir" class="level3 page-columns page-full">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="souvenir">Souvenir</h3>
<p>I finally got a cool souvenir! I know I should probably have been getting postcards or keychains or something in the cities I’ve visited for sentimental reasons but nothing has really called to me. Then, on the way to the Colosseum, I walked past an artist selling his drawings and they grabbed my attention. Ended up buying a three-panel piece that I loved. I’m going to try to find similar artwork during future trips.</p>
<div class="cell column-page quarto-layout-panel" data-layout-ncol="4" data-layout-nrow="1">
<div class="quarto-layout-row">
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 25.0%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 9 Rome/media/policeescort.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>Felt like a fever dream</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 25.0%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 9 Rome/media/painting.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>Love this simple style</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>


</section>
</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>Travel</category>
  <guid>https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 9 Rome/</guid>
  <pubDate>Wed, 02 Apr 2025 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 9 Rome/media/cover.JPG" medium="image"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>March 27, 2025</title>
  <dc:creator>Ian Beilfuss</dc:creator>
  <link>https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 8 Hockey Game and Munich/</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 




<section id="battle-for-prague" class="level2 page-columns page-full">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="battle-for-prague">Battle for Prague</h2>
<p>For most of the semester Česká Zemědělská Univerzita has nothing in the way of sports culture but wow did that change for the Battle of Prague. Once a semester the four main universities in Prague, Czech University of Life Sciences (ČZU), Czech Technical University (ČVUT), Charles University (UK), and the University of Economics (VŠE), come together for a tournament to determine the best team in Prague. During the fall semester play in games ČZU lost so we played for third place against VŠE this semester. Before the game, we all bought ČZU scarves to show our spirit. Some of us went early to the pregame parade to the stadium, complete with green hair spray, face paint, free beer, and a police escort. It was really entertaining to be walking with a bunch of Czech students and shouting chants without having any idea what they meant. At the stadium, we met up with the rest of the group and went into the stadium. We went to a ČZU game in February and were very disappointed by the lack of fan turnout and energy but tonight was completely different. The stadium was packed with fans from the four schools and energy was super high. I daresay there was more fan energy than at UW, or at least comparable to the UW student section at hockey games. We had a total blast even though ČZU was by far the worst team. We lost 4-2 and it was never a competition, I think the loss extends our losing streak to 9 games…</p>
<div class="cell column-page quarto-layout-panel" data-layout-nrow="1" data-layout-ncol="5">
<div class="quarto-layout-row">
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 20.0%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 8 Hockey Game and Munich/media/hockeygroup.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>Hockey game!</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 20.0%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 8 Hockey Game and Munich/media/hockeyrink.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>Go CZU!</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 20.0%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 8 Hockey Game and Munich/media/hockeyselfi.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>Huge fans</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 20.0%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 8 Hockey Game and Munich/media/patrick.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>Throwing up pitchforks for the farmers</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 20.0%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 8 Hockey Game and Munich/media/amelia.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>The green hair is a lot</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</section>
<section id="munich" class="level2 page-columns page-full">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="munich">Munich</h2>
<p>We had a fun but rainy weekend of sightseeing in Munich. We took a morning Flixbus and arrived in Munich at 2. After checking into the Wombat hostel, which I can highly recommend, we headed out to see the sights. We visited Munich Cathedral, St Peter’s Cathedral, and the New Town Hall in Munich’s central square, Marienplatz. St Peter’s Cathedral was beautiful with gold statues and murals, and we were lucky enough to have a live choir performing while we were there. We also paid to climb up the south tower for fantastic views of Munich. The view of the New Town Hall from the top was incredible, such a unique-looking building. We climbed down in time to catch the last of the three daily clock shows. The buildup of bells chiming took a full 10 minutes before the show started but it was worth the wait. Life-sized figures reenact jousting and dancing scenes from Munich’s history. It knocked the Prague astronomical clock’s show out of the water. For dinner, we went to Hofbräuhaus which was the largest restaurant I have ever been in, there was easily seating for 1000 people. We enjoyed some beer steins and traditional German food, it was a good time. Day two was rainy all morning. We were cold and wet on our walk to Eisbachwelle to see the river surfers but it was well worth it. They were incredible. What a cool thing to be able to do in the middle of a big city like Munich. After watching for a while we migrated to a St Patrick’s Day festival with live music but we were all so cold that we left pretty quickly. Near the festival, we stopped at Theatine Church and St.&nbsp;Michael München. Theatine Church had incredible stone carvings throughout the church, I can’t imagine the amount of work that went into it. Overall I enjoyed Munich, it was nice to walk from our hostel to all of the famous buildings in under half an hour. The food was good but expensive compared to Prague. I wish we had gotten better weather but we got so spoiled in Innsbruck that we were due for a not-as-good weather weekend, and it really only rained for a few hours the whole time.</p>
<div class="cell column-page quarto-layout-panel" data-layout-nrow="3" data-layout-ncol="4">
<div class="quarto-layout-row">
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 25.0%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 8 Hockey Game and Munich/media/municharrival.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>Arrived in Munich!</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 25.0%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 8 Hockey Game and Munich/media/grouppic1.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>Marienplatz Square</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 25.0%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 8 Hockey Game and Munich/media/newtownhall.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>The New Town Hall</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 25.0%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 8 Hockey Game and Munich/media/stpeters.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>Inside St Peter’s</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="quarto-layout-row">
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 25.0%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 8 Hockey Game and Munich/media/topofstpeters.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>At the top of St.&nbsp;Peter’s</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 25.0%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 8 Hockey Game and Munich/media/stpetersview.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>Fantastic View of Munich</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 25.0%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 8 Hockey Game and Munich/media/steins.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>Enjoying some steins</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 25.0%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 8 Hockey Game and Munich/media/grouppic2.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>Wet morning</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="quarto-layout-row">
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 25.0%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 8 Hockey Game and Munich/media/surfer.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>The surfers were so cool</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 25.0%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 8 Hockey Game and Munich/media/Theatinechurch.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>Inside Theatine Church</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 25.0%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 8 Hockey Game and Munich/media/Stmichael.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>Inside St Michael’s</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 25.0%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 8 Hockey Game and Munich/media/guinness.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>So close to a perfect split the G, happy St Patrick’s Day weekend!</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>Czechia</category>
  <guid>https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 8 Hockey Game and Munich/</guid>
  <pubDate>Thu, 27 Mar 2025 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 8 Hockey Game and Munich/media/newtownhall.JPG" medium="image"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>March 17, 2025</title>
  <dc:creator>Ian Beilfuss</dc:creator>
  <link>https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 7 Innsbruck/</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 




<section id="innsbruck" class="level2 page-columns page-full">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="innsbruck">Innsbruck</h2>
<p>Gonna be hard to top this weekend trip, Innsbruck is such a fantastic little city nestled in the Alps. Every time I’m in the mountains I’m blown away and question why I don’t live in a mountainous place all the time. Innsbruck is the kind of city I would love to live in when I’m older. Close to the mountains, not too big, relaxed culture, great public transport, and did I mention close to the mountains? We stayed at the Meininger Hotel in a six-person hostel room. It was super nice to have a room totally to ourselves to lay out all of our stinky skiing stuff at the end of the day. The hostel was across the street from the University of Innsbruck and the Inn River. I was very jealous. Every evening at sunset, students would sit on the side of the river, drink a beer, and chat. So naturally, we did the same the nights we were there. Everyone looked so happy and carefree, exactly my type of outdoor-loving people. Downtown Innsbruck was a fifteen-minute walk from the hostel and is super cute, but we really only went there to get food. The first night we went to Stiftskeller restaurant. I ordered a delicious mac and cheese dish, which even came with a salad! Prague could never. The food came in less than five minutes, it actually might have been the fastest restaurant service I’ve ever experienced. The second night we went to a pizza place called Trattoria-Pizzeria Due Sicilie. Such a cute little Italian place with great pizza and service for a pretty reasonable price by Innsbruck standards. Might have been my favorite meal to date. On the third night, we got takeaway burritos from Machete. The burritos were pretty average, I’ve had much better in Madison, but it was fun to eat along the river. I’m really hoping to be able to come back to Innsbruck in May to go hiking!</p>
<div class="cell column-page quarto-layout-panel" data-layout-nrow="2" data-layout-ncol="4">
<div class="quarto-layout-row">
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 25.0%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 7 Innsbruck/media/hostelview.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>The view from our room in the hostel</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 25.0%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 7 Innsbruck/media/sunset.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>Sunset over the Inn River</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 25.0%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 7 Innsbruck/media/nightriver.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>Innsbruck by night</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 25.0%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 7 Innsbruck/media/downtown.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>Downtown</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="quarto-layout-row">
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 25.0%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 7 Innsbruck/media/chairs.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>Night beers by the river</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 25.0%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 7 Innsbruck/media/Stiftskeller.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>Stiftskeller dinner</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 25.0%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 7 Innsbruck/media/pizzagroup.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>Trattoria-Pizzeria Due Sicilie</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</section>
<section id="skiing-at-schlick-2000" class="level2 page-columns page-full">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="skiing-at-schlick-2000">Skiing at Schlick 2000</h2>
<p>I love skiing in the Alps! We chose Schlick 2000 as our ski destination since it was an easy half-hour bus ride from Innsbruck. All in we spent $180 for two days of skiing and rentals which feels like a pretty great deal considering it would be more expensive to ski on crappy Midwest hills for the same amount of time. Schlick 2000 is hidden from the road by the crest of a smaller hill. It was amazing to take the gondola up and have the mountain and trails emerge in front of me. Schlick has 15 miles of groomed trails, which were starting to get repetitive by the end, but still a lot of fun, especially considering even the easiest trails near the gondola were the same difficulty as the hardest trails at the ski places I’ve been to near Madison. The most fun I had was skiing the off-piste routes with Aubrey. Lots of steep moguls and weaving around trees, it was a blast and I felt myself get more competent every run! I felt bad for the ski rental place because I put quite a few dents and scratches on my skis. Both days we skied were absolutely gorgeous. We had highs in the 40s and perfectly clear and sunny. I was skiing in only a sweatshirt and still was sweating. The snow wasn’t great, it was a weird combination of slushy at lower elevations and icy on the steeper runs near the top of the mountain. The off-piste snow was better, although a bit thin, and even the worst spots were totally manageable. One of the workers said they hadn’t gotten any snow since December, all of the snow was created. I think we might have gotten in on the last good weekend of skiing for the season.</p>
<div class="cell column-page quarto-layout-panel" data-layout-nrow="2" data-layout-ncol="3">
<div class="quarto-layout-row">
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 33.3%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 7 Innsbruck/media/map.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>Map of Schlick 2000</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 33.3%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 7 Innsbruck/media/group.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>The skiing group!</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 33.3%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 7 Innsbruck/media/selfi.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>Selfi at Panorama bar at the top of the mountain. Great lunch spot!</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="quarto-layout-row">
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 33.3%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 7 Innsbruck/media/lift.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>Lift to the top of the mountain</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 33.3%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 7 Innsbruck/media/offpiste1.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>Off-piste routes were so much fun</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 33.3%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 7 Innsbruck/media/offpiste2.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>View from the lift</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="cell page-columns page-full">
<div class="cell-output-display page-columns page-full">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center page-columns page-full">
<figure class="figure page-columns page-full">
<p class="page-columns page-full"><img src="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 7 Innsbruck/media/pano.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img column-page"></p>
<figcaption>Pano from the top of the mountain, hard to beat this view!</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
</div>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>Travel</category>
  <guid>https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 7 Innsbruck/</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 17 Mar 2025 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 7 Innsbruck/media/nightriver.JPG" medium="image"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>March 11, 2025</title>
  <dc:creator>Ian Beilfuss</dc:creator>
  <link>https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 6 Budapest/</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 




<section id="budapest" class="level2 page-columns page-full">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="budapest">Budapest</h2>
<p>Budapest was amazing and a perfect destination for our first trip out of Czechia. The city felt very similar to Prague in a lot of respects. From a tourist perspective, Budapest has more things to do and visit than Prague since it’s a fair bit larger, but it lacks the quaintness that makes Prague so special. The public transportation was fantastic, possibly even better than Prague’s, which is a high bar to pass, and the metro stations were super unique looking. That being said, there were a lot more cars which noticeably detracted from my enjoyment. The architectural style of most of the buildings felt very similar, with lots of ornate buildings and red roofs. I find it very interesting that neither Prague nor Budapest has anything in the way of skyscrapers. Budapest technically has one but it would barely count by US standards. We stayed at the Maverick Central Market Hostel, which I can highly recommend. It was cheap, clean, a great location, and let us store our luggage for free before check-in.</p>
<div class="cell column-page quarto-layout-panel" data-layout-ncol="3">
<div class="quarto-layout-row">
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 33.3%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 6 Budapest/media/weirdmetrostation.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>This metro station looked so space age</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 33.3%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 6 Budapest/media/cutemetrostation.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>I love how quaint this metro station was</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 33.3%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 6 Budapest/media/hostel.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>My 8 bed mixed dormitory in the hostel</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</section>
<section id="friday" class="level2 page-columns page-full">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="friday">Friday</h2>
<p>After taking the overnight Flixbus from Prague, we arrived half asleep to Budapest at 6 am. Thankfully the thermal baths awaited us. Three hours soaking in warm pools and saunas was so delightful, I need to find something similar in Prague. I can highly recommend Lukacs Baths if you’re ever in Budapest, only $10 for the whole day! We spent the rest of the day sightseeing! First on the agenda was St.&nbsp;Stephen’s Basilica, I didn’t have time to go inside, but the outside was very impressive. Next up was the Hungarian Parliament Building, which I would put in the running for most beautiful parliament building in the world, especially when it’s lit up at night. From there we went to the Dohány Street Synagogue, the largest synagogue in Europe. Tickets to go inside were $30, unfortunately, but we walked around the outside and read up on the building’s history. Last on the landmarks list for the day was the Museum of Hungarian Agriculture, which looked like a castle, with a moat and everything. For dinner we went to a restaurant called Babka, I ordered the Jemen Goulash. It was delicious and the presentation was amazing.</p>
<div class="cell column-page quarto-layout-panel" data-layout-nrow="2" data-layout-ncol="4">
<div class="quarto-layout-row">
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 25.0%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 6 Budapest/media/arrival.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>Welcome to Budapest at 6am!</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 25.0%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 6 Budapest/media/bathhouse.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>Loved the thermal bath house</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 25.0%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 6 Budapest/media/parliment.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>Hungarian Parliament, the largest building in Hungry</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 25.0%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 6 Budapest/media/parlimentnight.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>So beautiful lit up at night</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="quarto-layout-row">
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 25.0%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 6 Budapest/media/ststeven.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>St.&nbsp;Stephen’s Basilica</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 25.0%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 6 Budapest/media/synagogue.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>Dohány Street Synagogue</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 25.0%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 6 Budapest/media/castle.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>Museum of Hungarian Agriculture</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 25.0%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 6 Budapest/media/dinner.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>Goulash dinner</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</section>
<section id="saturday" class="level2 page-columns page-full">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="saturday">Saturday</h2>
<p>Another packed day of Budapest sightseeing. We started with Budapest Castle. Learning about the history of the Siege of Budapest by the Soviets and Romanians at the end of World War II was sobering. I’m amazed at how well the city has recovered after having its population and buildings so decimated. We didn’t end up going into the Castle to the history museum, but the view of Budapest from the top was beautiful. We managed to be timed perfectly for the hourly changing of the guards, I like that ceremonial stuff like that still has a place. Next we visited the Church of Saint Matthias which is one of the most incredible buildings I’ve ever seen. The hexagon tiling on the roof and the golden interior was all so amazing. For sunset we went to Gellért Hill, which has beautiful bluffs that overlook the city center. We ended the night with a prosecco cruise. Unlimited prosecco and truffle pasta is a dangerous combination but we had a great time.</p>
<div class="cell column-page quarto-layout-panel" data-layout-nrow="2" data-layout-ncol="3">
<div class="quarto-layout-row">
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 33.3%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><video src="media/guardchange.mp4" class="img-fluid" controls=""><a href="media/guardchange.mp4">Video</a></video></p>
<figcaption>The hourly guard change</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 33.3%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 6 Budapest/media/matthiaschurch.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>Matthias Church!</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 33.3%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 6 Budapest/media/matthiasinterior.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>Matthias Church interior</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="quarto-layout-row">
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 33.3%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 6 Budapest/media/wholegroup.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>Group picture on Gellért Hill</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 33.3%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 6 Budapest/media/proseccocruise.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>Prosecco Cruise</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="cell page-columns page-full">
<div class="cell-output-display page-columns page-full">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center page-columns page-full">
<figure class="figure page-columns page-full">
<p class="page-columns page-full"><img src="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 6 Budapest/media/pano.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img column-page"></p>
<figcaption>Sunset panorama, Budapest is beautiful</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
</div>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>Travel</category>
  <guid>https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 6 Budapest/</guid>
  <pubDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2025 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 6 Budapest/media/cover.JPG" medium="image"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>March 10, 2025</title>
  <dc:creator>Ian Beilfuss</dc:creator>
  <link>https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 5 Hiking Trip and Bone Church/</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 




<section id="hiking-trip" class="level2 page-columns page-full">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="hiking-trip">Hiking Trip</h2>
<p>On February 8th, ESN organized a hiking trip in the Czech countryside near Kamenný Přívoz village, about an hour’s train ride south of Prague (I love the train network here!!). We hiked seven miles following the Sázava river. The landscape reminded me a lot of Oregon, with rolling hills and bluffs, and lots of evergreens. Getting out of the city on a hike and talking with other CZU students was great! My favorite part was the small houses built on the side of the bluffs! I have no idea how they get down to their houses, let alone how they built them. It looked like such a peaceful life living on the river, I’m envious. I want to do more hiking day trips around Czechia, Bohemian Switzerland National Park might be next.</p>
<div class="cell quarto-layout-panel page-columns page-full" data-layout-ncol="1">
<div class="quarto-layout-row page-full">
<div class="quarto-layout-cell page-columns page-full" style="flex-basis: 100.0%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center page-columns page-full">
<figure class="figure page-columns page-full">
<p class="page-columns page-full"><img src="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 5 Hiking Trip and Bone Church/media/hikeroute.PNG" class="img-fluid figure-img column-page"></p>
<figcaption>Hiking route!</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="cell column-page quarto-layout-panel" data-layout-ncol="4" data-layout-nrow="2">
<div class="quarto-layout-row">
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 25.0%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 5 Hiking Trip and Bone Church/media/hiking.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>Hiking</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 25.0%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 5 Hiking Trip and Bone Church/media/river1.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>Beautiful views of Sázava river</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 25.0%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 5 Hiking Trip and Bone Church/media/river2.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>Sázava</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 25.0%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 5 Hiking Trip and Bone Church/media/bridge.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>Rail bridge</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="quarto-layout-row">
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 25.0%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 5 Hiking Trip and Bone Church/media/icicle.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>We found some super cool icicle formations</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 25.0%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 5 Hiking Trip and Bone Church/media/house1.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>House on the bluff</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 25.0%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 5 Hiking Trip and Bone Church/media/house2.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>This was my favorite house, how to they get to it?!</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 25.0%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 5 Hiking Trip and Bone Church/media/house3.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>Some more bluff houses</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</section>
<section id="kutná-hora" class="level2 page-columns page-full">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="kutná-hora">Kutná Hora</h2>
<p>On February 16, our group took a day trip to Kutná Hora, which was also just an hour away by train (I promise I’ll stop praising the trains eventually). Kutná Hora is known for the Sedlec Ossuary, also called the Bone Church. The inside of the church is pretty incredible, there are pyramid stacks and hanging arrangements built from thousands of bones of people from the 14th and 15th centuries who died from the bubonic plague and Hussite Wars. We also visited the Cathedral of Assumption of Our Lady and St.&nbsp;John the Baptist. The interior had a lot of beautiful murals and gold statues. I love all of the old churches and cathedrals in Europe, even the ones in small towns are so amazingly intricate.</p>
<div class="cell column-page quarto-layout-panel" data-layout-ncol="3" data-layout-nrow="2">
<div class="quarto-layout-row">
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 33.3%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 5 Hiking Trip and Bone Church/media/bonechurch.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>Sedlec Ossuary doesn’t allow photos but I downloaded this one from the official website</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 33.3%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 5 Hiking Trip and Bone Church/media/cathedralexterior.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>Cathedral exterior</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 33.3%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 5 Hiking Trip and Bone Church/media/cathedralinterior.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>Cathedral interior</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="quarto-layout-row">
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 33.3%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 5 Hiking Trip and Bone Church/media/organ.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>Organ</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 33.3%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 5 Hiking Trip and Bone Church/media/shrine.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>So many gold statues</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 33.3%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 5 Hiking Trip and Bone Church/media/mural.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>I like this mural style</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>Czechia</category>
  <guid>https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 5 Hiking Trip and Bone Church/</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 10 Mar 2025 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 5 Hiking Trip and Bone Church/media/kutnahora.JPG" medium="image"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>March 5, 2025</title>
  <dc:creator>Ian Beilfuss</dc:creator>
  <link>https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 4 People/</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 




<section id="the-uw-group" class="level2 page-columns page-full">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="the-uw-group">The UW Group</h2>
<p>Everyone I’ve met here is so friendly and fun! There are ten of us from UW living in Dormitory JIH so we quickly became good friends. Nine of us started this semester, and Sam started fall semester and is staying the full year, so he’s been a great resource for things to do in Prague. I didn’t know any of them before coming to Prague, so it’s been great to meet new people I’ll remain friends with back at UW.</p>
<div class="cell quarto-layout-panel page-columns page-full" data-layout-ncol="1">
<div class="quarto-layout-row page-full">
<div class="quarto-layout-cell page-columns page-full" style="flex-basis: 100.0%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center page-columns page-full">
<figure class="figure page-columns page-full">
<p class="page-columns page-full"><img src="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 4 People/media/dancinghouse.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img column-page"></p>
<figcaption>The UW group! Boys from left to right: Rafe, Peter, me, Patrick (roommate), Tristan. Girls from left to right: Amelia, Maddie, Violette, Aubrey</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="cell column-page quarto-layout-panel" data-layout-ncol="2">
<div class="quarto-layout-row">
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 50.0%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 4 People/media/vitkov.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>Another group pic with Sam 4th from the left</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 50.0%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 4 People/media/firstnight.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>First night</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</section>
<section id="the-international-group" class="level2 page-columns page-full">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="the-international-group">The International Group</h2>
<p>The ESN organized events have been a great way to meet other international students! During the first events, we met a great group of French who have quickly become our closest non-American friends. Artemis from Greece has also joined our close circle, and came with us to Budapest last weekend! I’ve also become friends with people from Germany, Austria, South Korea, Turkey and Brazil! Many of them live at the external dormitory, which is half an hour from campus, so it can be difficult to make plans, but it’s fun to see them at classes and ESN events. I haven’t met any Czechs yet, the ESN events aren’t geared towards Czech students and my classes are mainly international students. I have embarrassingly few group pictures with everyone, I’ll have to work on that.</p>
<div class="cell column-page quarto-layout-panel" data-layout-ncol="2">
<div class="quarto-layout-row">
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 50.0%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 4 People/media/czechdinner.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>Czech dinner with the French! From left to right: me, Patrick, Ugo, Rafe, Anaëlle, Liam, Tristan, Séraphine, Mathilde</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 50.0%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 4 People/media/charlesbridge.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>Group pic on Charles Bridge</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>Czechia</category>
  <guid>https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 4 People/</guid>
  <pubDate>Wed, 05 Mar 2025 06:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 4 People/media/vitkov.JPG" medium="image"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>March 4, 2025</title>
  <dc:creator>Ian Beilfuss</dc:creator>
  <link>https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 3 Favorite Places in Prague/</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 




<section id="charles-bridge" class="level2 page-columns page-full">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="charles-bridge">Charles Bridge</h2>
<p>The most famous bridge in Prague, so many statues and it gets lit up beautifully at night.</p>
<div class="cell column-page quarto-layout-panel" data-layout-ncol="2">
<div class="quarto-layout-row">
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 50.0%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 3 Favorite Places in Prague/media/charlesbridgeday.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>Brdige by day</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 50.0%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 3 Favorite Places in Prague/media/charlesbridgenight.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>Lit up at night</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</section>
<section id="astronomical-clock" class="level2 page-columns page-full">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="astronomical-clock">Astronomical Clock</h2>
<p>The oldest astronomical clock in the world! Constructed back in the early 15th century. The clock itself is fascinatingly intricate and there’s a cool little moving show when the clock strikes the hour.</p>
<div class="cell quarto-layout-panel page-columns page-full" data-layout-ncol="2">
<div class="quarto-layout-row page-full">
<div class="quarto-layout-cell page-columns page-full" style="flex-basis: 50.0%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center page-columns page-full">
<figure class="figure page-columns page-full">
<p class="page-columns page-full"><img src="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 3 Favorite Places in Prague/media/astronomicalclock.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img column-page"></p>
<figcaption>The astronomical clock with the Church of Our Lady before Týn</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 50.0%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><video src="media/astronomicalclockvid.MOV" class="img-fluid" controls=""><a href="media/astronomicalclockvid.MOV">Video</a></video></p>
<figcaption>Hourly show!</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</section>
<section id="prague-castle" class="level2 page-columns page-full">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="prague-castle">Prague Castle</h2>
<p>Probably the most famous building in Prague. The Castle itself I found a little underwhelming because in my head castle mean medieval castle with turrets and a moat. That being said St.&nbsp;Vitus Cathedral in the central of the castle is beautiful and the view of Prague from the castle is incredible! I’ll have to go back at some point and pay to go inside the castle to see the museum and photo gallery.</p>
<div class="cell column-page quarto-layout-panel" data-layout-ncol="2">
<div class="quarto-layout-row">
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 50.0%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 3 Favorite Places in Prague/media/praguecastle.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>View from the front of Prague Castle</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 50.0%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 3 Favorite Places in Prague/media/praguecathedral.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>Prague Cathedral inside the center countyard of the castle</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</section>
<section id="lennon-wall" class="level2 page-columns page-full">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="lennon-wall">Lennon Wall</h2>
<p>Probably the coolest mural wall I’ve seen. So much history in one place. The tradition of painting the wall started during the Soviet oppression of Czechia as a way to defy Soviet control. The Soviets would paid over the wall frequently but the wall would be filled with paintings and inspirational messages the very next day. Our tour guide said that now they host poem days where they string up paper and anyone can come and share a poem for others to read.</p>
<div class="cell quarto-layout-panel page-columns page-full" data-layout-ncol="1">
<div class="quarto-layout-row page-full">
<div class="quarto-layout-cell page-columns page-full" style="flex-basis: 100.0%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center page-columns page-full">
<figure class="figure page-columns page-full">
<p class="page-columns page-full"><img src="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 3 Favorite Places in Prague/media/lennonwall.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img column-page"></p>
<figcaption>Lennon Wall</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</section>
<section id="vítkov" class="level2 page-columns page-full">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="vítkov">Vítkov</h2>
<p>Vítkov is a national monument and park on top of a large hill with great views of the city. Would recommend as a sunset location! The monument is super impressive too.</p>
<div class="cell column-page quarto-layout-panel" data-layout-ncol="2">
<div class="quarto-layout-row">
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 50.0%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 3 Favorite Places in Prague/media/vitkovsunset.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>Beautiful sunset!</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 50.0%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 3 Favorite Places in Prague/media/vitkov.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>Vítkov monument</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</section>
<section id="dancing-house" class="level2 page-columns page-full">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="dancing-house">Dancing House</h2>
<p>Dancing house was one of our first destinations as a group. It’s a super cool looking hotel with a rooftop bar and a great view of the Vltava River and downtown Prague!</p>
<div class="cell column-page quarto-layout-panel" data-layout-ncol="3">
<div class="quarto-layout-row">
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 33.3%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 3 Favorite Places in Prague/media/dancinghouse.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>Dancing House!</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 33.3%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 3 Favorite Places in Prague/media/dancinghousegrouppic.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>Group pic at the end of our first full day</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 33.3%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 3 Favorite Places in Prague/media/dancinghouseview.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>The view from the rooftop bar</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>Czechia</category>
  <guid>https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 3 Favorite Places in Prague/</guid>
  <pubDate>Tue, 04 Mar 2025 06:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 3 Favorite Places in Prague/media/bridge.JPG" medium="image"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>March 3, 2025</title>
  <dc:creator>Ian Beilfuss</dc:creator>
  <link>https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 2 Initial Thoughts About Prague/</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 




<p>Prague is amazing! I’m sure anyone who’s visited here feels the same, it really is a magical city. I love the architecture and the cobbled streets. Everything feels like it has so much more character and life than anywhere in the US.</p>
<section id="public-transport" class="level2 page-columns page-full">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="public-transport">Public Transport</h2>
<p>I think my favorite part about Prague might be the public transport. With the student pass, I pay five dollars a month for unlimited access to the metro, buses, and trams to get anywhere in the city. The longest I’ve ever had to wait for transit is about ten minutes, and it’s always easy to grab a bus into the city from Campus. All of the metros and metro stations are very clean and I’ve never been worried about my safety or the safety of my belongings even when I’ve been riding solo. The metros cover the city really well. Most places I’ve been are less than a 10 minutes walk from the a metro station. It’s going to be difficult to go back to Madison Transit after getting spoiled here. The ticketing system here is fascinating to me. It’s basically an honor system. You buy a pass for a certain amount of time on the PID app but you never have to scan it to get on the transit. On occasion, transit police will come around and ask to see your ticket, but I’ve only been asked once a week at most. The fine if you don’t have a ticket is significant at $40, so buying a ticket is always worth it, but I can’t help but think about how much an honor system like this would get exploited in the US.</p>
<div class="cell column-page quarto-layout-panel" data-layout-ncol="2">
<div class="quarto-layout-row">
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 50.0%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 2 Initial Thoughts About Prague/media/decenttometro.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>The decent to the metro</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 50.0%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 2 Initial Thoughts About Prague/media/metro.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>The metro</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="cell column-page quarto-layout-panel" data-layout-ncol="2">
<div class="quarto-layout-row">
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 50.0%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 2 Initial Thoughts About Prague/media/packedbus.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>The buses to campus can be absolutely packed during the school day but thankfully they come every five minutes</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 50.0%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 2 Initial Thoughts About Prague/media/tramcables.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>There are cables for the trams everywhere!</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<p>So far I’ve only used the train system twice to other parts of Czechia, more on that in a future post. I’m amazed by the ability to go to almost any small town in Czechia just by train. It is for sure less efficient than driving, but trains run once an hour, sometimes more frequently, so commuting to Prague for work or taking day trips around Czechia only by train is totally feasible. I can’t see the US ever implementing something like this but I love it so much.</p>
<div class="cell column-page quarto-layout-panel" data-layout-ncol="2">
<div class="quarto-layout-row">
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 50.0%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 2 Initial Thoughts About Prague/media/trainstation.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>So many train tracks from the central station!</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 50.0%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 2 Initial Thoughts About Prague/media/trainstop.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>Waiting for the train on the way back from a hike</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</section>
<section id="drinking-culture" class="level2 page-columns page-full">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="drinking-culture">Drinking Culture</h2>
<p>It’s hard to talk about Prague without talking about beer. Seriously, it feels like nearly everything I do in Prague involves drinking. It’s easy to see how Czechia has by far the highest beer consumption of any country. The get-to-know-you events (human bingo, trivia, tour of Prague) for students studying abroad put on by the European Student Network either took place at a bar or ended at one. Even the dorms on campus have bars on the ground floor, not to mention the CZU club. It’s very jarring to see the heavy drinking culture in Madison get outmatched almost instantly in Prague. That being said, there is plenty to do in Prague that doesn’t involve drinking, it’s just harder to find places to hang out that aren’t bars than I would like.</p>
<div class="cell column-page quarto-layout-panel" data-layout-ncol="2">
<div class="quarto-layout-row">
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 50.0%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 2 Initial Thoughts About Prague/media/pong.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>ESN organized beer pong</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 50.0%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 2 Initial Thoughts About Prague/media/beer.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>The beer heads are so huge here</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</section>
<section id="food" class="level2 page-columns page-full">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="food">Food</h2>
<p>The food in Prague has been great so far, and more importantly it’s cheap! I try to cook as many of my meals as I can, but when I go out, most of the places are $7 or less for a full meal, although we mostly end up going to chains. Some of my favorites include Bageterie Boulevard, a Czech chain that serves delicious warm baguette sandwiches, Vietfood, which serves surprisingly good Vietnamese and other asian dishes, and any kebab shop we can find. I think kebabs make up half of the meals I’ve eaten in Prague, and that’s not even that much of an exaggeration. Kebab in Prague means a tortilla filled with gyro meat, cabbage, lettuce, onion, garlic sauce, and chilli sauce wrapped up like a burrito. There are kebab shops all over Prague, it’s just too easy and delicious to pass up.</p>
<div class="cell column-page quarto-layout-panel" data-layout-ncol="2">
<div class="quarto-layout-row">
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 50.0%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 2 Initial Thoughts About Prague/media/kebab.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>My first meal in Prague was a kebab!</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 50.0%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 2 Initial Thoughts About Prague/media/vietfood.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>Pad thai</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<p>Embarrassingly, I’ve only gotten Czech food one time, and while it was pretty decent, there’s a good reason Czechia isn’t known for its cuisine. I want to go out for Czech food again in the future, but it’s just so convenient to go to my standbys of Bageterie Boulevard, Vietfood, or kebab.</p>
<div class="cell column-page quarto-layout-panel" data-layout-ncol="2">
<div class="quarto-layout-row">
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 50.0%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 2 Initial Thoughts About Prague/media/czechfood.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>Czech food!</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 50.0%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 2 Initial Thoughts About Prague/media/czechdinner.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>Czech dinner with study abroad friends!</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>Czechia</category>
  <guid>https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 2 Initial Thoughts About Prague/</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 03 Mar 2025 06:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 2 Initial Thoughts About Prague/media/praguesunset.JPG" medium="image"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Feb 26, 2025</title>
  <dc:creator>Ian Beilfuss</dc:creator>
  <link>https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 1 Initial Thoughts About CZU/</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 




<p>Hello from Prague! This is my third week in Prague and I’m starting to feel pretty settled in so I decided it’s time to do my first blog post! The last three weeks have been a blur, it simultaneously feels like I’ve been here for no time at all and also multiple months. I’m going to try to post weekly forward, but I’m going to be playing catch up for the last few weeks first.</p>
<section id="czu" class="level2 page-columns page-full">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="czu">CZU</h2>
<p>I’m spending my semester abroad at the Czech University of Life Sciences (Česká Zemědělská Univerzita in Czech). The university is in Prague 6, about seven miles from the city center, which ends up being around a half hour away on public transport. The campus itself is pretty small, especially compared to the sprawling University of Wisconsin I’m used to. It’s nice to have all my classes within a quick 7-minute walk, and for the campus to be mostly car-free. There are around 20,000 students who study at CZU, but it honestly feels a fair bit smaller. My largest class only has like 15 students. The campus buildings feel new, or at least recently remodeled, with nice classrooms and layouts. Because the university is geared towards agriculture and environmental students, there’s a good amount of greenspace and even a small farm with llamas!</p>
<div class="cell column-page quarto-layout-panel" data-layout-ncol="4">
<div class="quarto-layout-row">
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 25.0%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 1 Initial Thoughts About CZU/media/campusmap.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>Map of the CZU campus</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 25.0%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 1 Initial Thoughts About CZU/media/snowycampus1.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>Campus is beautiful when it snows!</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 25.0%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 1 Initial Thoughts About CZU/media/czufarm.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>The CZU farm with pigs and cows!</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 25.0%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 1 Initial Thoughts About CZU/media/llamas.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>Campus llamas!</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</section>
<section id="classes" class="level2 page-columns page-full">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="classes">Classes</h2>
<p>Classes themselves are probably the biggest letdown of the whole experience so far. I’m used to the rigor of UW classes so it’s jarring to only meet for classes once a week for an hour and a half lecture, and then have virtually no assignments to do between classes. While at CZU I’m in the Faculty of Environmental Sciences and am taking all ecology courses: Wetland Conservation and Management, Forest Ecology, Non-forest Vegetation, and Ecosystem Conservation and Management. Two of my courses have twenty-minute presentations as the only assignment besides the final, another one has some short readings. My last class doesn’t have any assignments, just a couple of half-day field trips, which hopefully are a good experience. It’s nice to have more free time than in Madison, but I am quickly realizing that I need the consistency of assignments to occupy my days and make me feel like I’m doing something productive. The lectures do teach a fair bit of information, but without assignments, I don’t think very much of it will sink in. I’m just hoping I take some knowledge away from the semester so the courses aren’t a total waste.</p>
<div class="cell column-page quarto-layout-panel" data-layout-ncol="2">
<div class="quarto-layout-row">
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 50.0%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 1 Initial Thoughts About CZU/media/facultyofenvirosci.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>Building for the Faculty of Environmental Sciences, although none of my courses are here</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 50.0%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 1 Initial Thoughts About CZU/media/wetlandecologypowerpoint.png" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>The Powerpoints for my Wetland Conservation and Management Course leave a lot to be desired</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</section>
<section id="dorms" class="level2 page-columns page-full">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="dorms">Dorms</h2>
<p>The dorms here are less than ideal. I know all dorms are pretty bad, but these seem even worse than where I stayed for freshman year at UW. There are no common rooms, just a very cramped room with a ping-pong table. The dorm rooms are reasonably big but the linoleum floor collects dust like nobody’s business. We share a bathroom with two people in the room next door, which isn’t too bad, but the bathroom looks like it hasn’t been updated since the 50s and all the cabinets are rusted shut. It’s all manageable because the room costs less than $300 per month, but we know people in the same dorm who have a brand new updated bathroom despite paying the same, so we’re salty. The one good thing I can say about the bathroom is that the water pressure and heat are top notch. For cooking, the dorm room comes with a mini fridge and small hot plate, which just barely does the job. I’ve been able to make breakfast burritos, pasta, and curry, but only having one burner feels very limiting. Thankfully the grocery store is only a 10 minute bus ride away and I shop multiple times per week so the mini fridge isn’t too restrictive.</p>
<div class="cell column-page quarto-layout-panel" data-layout-ncol="4">
<div class="quarto-layout-row">
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 25.0%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 1 Initial Thoughts About CZU/media/dormexterior.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>Kolej JIH exterior</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 25.0%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 1 Initial Thoughts About CZU/media/dormbedroom.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>My dorm room</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 25.0%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 1 Initial Thoughts About CZU/media/dormkitchen.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>Cooking all of my meals on one hotplate is not going to be enjoyable</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 25.0%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 1 Initial Thoughts About CZU/media/dormbathroom.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>very subpar bathroom, if only the cabinets weren’t rusted shut</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="cell column-page quarto-layout-panel" data-layout-ncol="4">
<div class="quarto-layout-row">
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 25.0%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 1 Initial Thoughts About CZU/media/dormview.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>The view from my dorm room is fantatic!</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 25.0%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 1 Initial Thoughts About CZU/media/clearedptich.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>Even better after snow!</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 25.0%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 1 Initial Thoughts About CZU/media/breakfastburrito.jpg" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>hot plate breakfast burrito</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 25.0%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 1 Initial Thoughts About CZU/media/pestopasta.jpg" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>hot plate pesto pasta</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>Czechia</category>
  <guid>https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 1 Initial Thoughts About CZU/</guid>
  <pubDate>Wed, 26 Feb 2025 06:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://ian88.github.io/blogs/Post 1 Initial Thoughts About CZU/Media/campusmap.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg"/>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
