<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss  xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" 
      xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" 
      xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" 
      xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" 
      version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>Ian Beilfuss</title>
<link>https://ian88.github.io/CartographicProjects.html</link>
<atom:link href="https://ian88.github.io/CartographicProjects.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
<description></description>
<generator>quarto-1.8.26</generator>
<lastBuildDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 06:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
<item>
  <title>The Long Winter</title>
  <dc:creator>Ian Beilfuss</dc:creator>
  <link>https://ian88.github.io/cartography/The Long Winter/</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 




<p>The Long Winter was created for the final project of Geography 572, Graphic Design in Cartography at UW-Madison. This project was created with support from the International Crane Foundation.</p>
<p>eBird has become one of the largest citizen science project in the world and can provide amazing information about the spatial location and density of bird. The project provided me with a valuable introduction to processing eBird data and using it to make spatial correlations.</p>
<p>ArcGIS StoryMaps was chosen as the medium for my project to make it more interactive and to provide more information than I could convey through an infographic. The processing of eBird data was done in QGIS and R, with coding help from ChatGPT. All maps were made in QGIS, with design enhancements made with Adobe Illustrator.&nbsp;</p>
<p>I hope this story can provide a visually compelling and informative look at Sandhill Crane wintering patterns in California.</p>
<iframe src="https://storymaps.arcgis.com/stories/380e214aa5ba41b482dc9657b3d7af90" width="100%" height="800px" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="" allow="geolocation">
</iframe>
<p><a href="https://arcg.is/0jqCiH0" target="_blank">View The Long Winter in a new tab</a></p>



 ]]></description>
  <category>Interactive</category>
  <category>Thematic</category>
  <guid>https://ian88.github.io/cartography/The Long Winter/</guid>
  <pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 06:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://ian88.github.io/cartography/The Long Winter/media/cover.png" medium="image" type="image/png" height="70" width="144"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Equity of Public Transit Access to Hiking Trails in San Francisco, CA</title>
  <dc:creator>Ian Beilfuss and WIll McAllister</dc:creator>
  <link>https://ian88.github.io/cartography/San Francisco Trail Equity/</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 




<p>This semester-long collaborative project with Will McAllister for Geography 578: Applications of GIS provides an introductory analysis of the equity of public transit access to hiking trails in San Francisco, CA. Through our analysis, we evaluated the following research statement:</p>
<p>The San Francisco Bay Area is known for its hiking trails, but public transportation inequities are a potential barrier for many communities to access them. We seek to evaluate access to unpaved hiking trails in the San Francisco Bay Area by creating a distance matrix of the duration of travel by public transportation from census block group centroids in the City of San Francisco to trailheads. We will then overlay demographic data to understand how public transit access to trails varies across different socioeconomic and racial groups.</p>
<p>Using San Francisco and the Bay Area as our study area, we evaluated trail systems in the area and removed any that failed to meet our 5+ mile length and unpaved criteria. Next, we created trailheads by snapping trails to Open Street Network roads.</p>
<div class="cell column-page quarto-layout-panel" data-layout-ncol="3">
<div class="quarto-layout-row">
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 33.3%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://ian88.github.io/cartography/San Francisco Trail Equity/media/Study Area.png" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>The study area for our analysis, with San Francisco highlighted in purple</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 33.3%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://ian88.github.io/cartography/San Francisco Trail Equity/media/5+ Mile Unpaved Trails.png" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>Trails that met our 5+ mile unpaved criteria</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 33.3%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://ian88.github.io/cartography/San Francisco Trail Equity/media/Accessible Trailheads.png" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>Trailheads that are accessible within a 2.5-hour transit journey</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<p>Using the R5 routing engine within the r5r R package, we calculated the total travel time and number of transit legs to reach each trailhead from each San Francisco block group centroid.</p>
<div class="cell">
<div class="cell-output-display">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://ian88.github.io/cartography/San Francisco Trail Equity/media/Reachable Trails.png" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>The number of trails that are accessible by public transport in under a 2.5-hour journey from each block group centroid. San Francisco public transportation routes are overlaid to make trends more visible</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<p>We assigned a Trail Accessibility Score for each transit journey by summing the Duration Score and Rides Score, using the following scoring:</p>
<div class="cell">
<div class="cell-output-display">
<div>
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://ian88.github.io/cartography/San Francisco Trail Equity/media/Scoring.png" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="cell">
<div class="cell-output-display">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://ian88.github.io/cartography/San Francisco Trail Equity/media/Trail Accessibility.png" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>The average Trail Accessibility Score for each block group. San Francisco public transportation routes are overlaid to make trends more visible</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<p>For each 2020 Census San Francisco block group, we evaluated vulnerability based on three demographic variables: income, race, and vehicle access. We then overlaid the average Trail Accessibility Scores to draw conclusions about the equity of trail accessibility.</p>
<div class="cell">
<div class="cell-output-display">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://ian88.github.io/cartography/San Francisco Trail Equity/media/Trail x Income.png" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>Trail accessibility by income vulnerability. San Francisco public transportation routes are overlaid to make trends more visible</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="cell">
<div class="cell-output-display">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://ian88.github.io/cartography/San Francisco Trail Equity/media/Trail x Race.png" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>Trail accessibility by race vulnerability. San Francisco public transportation routes are overlaid to make trends more visible</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="cell">
<div class="cell-output-display">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://ian88.github.io/cartography/San Francisco Trail Equity/media/Trail x Vehicle.png" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>Trail accessibility by vehicle vulnerability. San Francisco public transportation routes are overlaid to make trends more visible</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<p>From our analysis we found that income or race vulnerability does not significantly affect the ease of accessing hiking trails. This is likely because San Francisco has a robust public transit network, providing all communities with accessible transit. However, we found that vehicle vulnerability has some correlation with better trail accessibility. This makes some intuitive sense because the majority of the block groups with high vehicle vulnerability are located near the BART line. For people living in these block groups, a car may not be as necessary because there is a good public transportation system. However, further research is needed before more concrete conclusions can be drawn.</p>
<p><a href="media/Full Report.pdf" target="_blank">Learn more about the background, detailed methodology, and expanded discussion of our project by clicking to read the full project report</a></p>



 ]]></description>
  <category>Static</category>
  <category>Thematic</category>
  <guid>https://ian88.github.io/cartography/San Francisco Trail Equity/</guid>
  <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 06:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://ian88.github.io/cartography/San Francisco Trail Equity/media/Trail Accessibility.png" medium="image" type="image/png" height="110" width="144"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>V: Custom Tileset</title>
  <dc:creator>Ian Beilfuss</dc:creator>
  <link>https://ian88.github.io/cartography/V - Custom Tileset/</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 




<p>For this project, I created a custom tileset in MapBox Studio based on V for Vendetta, a 1982 graphic novel written by Alan Moore and illustrated by David Lloyd, and the 2005 film adaptation, directed by James McTeigue.</p>
<p>The tileset uses fonts and colors drawn directly from the graphic novel and film to mimic the muted, noir aesthetic of V for Vendetta. Additionally, I brought in pictorial elements from the graphic novel, including the Guy Faux mask as a city indicator and an explosion to cover the city’s extent. More details on the design choices I implemented can be found in the explainer below.&nbsp;</p>

<iframe width="100%" height="800px" src="https://api.mapbox.com/styles/v1/ibeilfuss/cmgkzx2yz001601rtbqvf8byd.html?title=view&amp;access_token=pk.eyJ1IjoiaWJlaWxmdXNzIiwiYSI6ImNtZ2t6aHNjZjB5YzQyam4yZGVrMm83bTIifQ.yt5N25nrRBAhSI_rE8WS1A&amp;zoomwheel=true&amp;fresh=true#0/0/0" title="V" style="border:none;">
</iframe>

<iframe src="https://ian88.github.io/V_Tileset.github.io/" width="100%" height="600px" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="" allow="geolocation">
</iframe>
<p><a href="https://ian88.github.io/V_Tileset.github.io/" target="_blank">View the Explainer in a New Tab</a></p>



 ]]></description>
  <category>Interactive</category>
  <category>Reference</category>
  <guid>https://ian88.github.io/cartography/V - Custom Tileset/</guid>
  <pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 06:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://ian88.github.io/cartography/V - Custom Tileset/media/cover.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Land on Fire</title>
  <dc:creator>Ian Beilfuss</dc:creator>
  <link>https://ian88.github.io/cartography/Land on Fire/</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 




<p>As you may have seen, this is my second cartographic project that centers around the California Wildfires. I’ve been following the trends, causes, and effects of wildfires in California for multiple years. I created Land on Fire to share what I have learned while following this story.</p>
<p>The severity of wildfires has been well-documented in the media, particularly over the past decade. However, many of these stories only discuss the extent, severity, and firefighting techniques used in association with the fire. I wanted to ensure that I was telling a more comprehensive story to help contextualize the root causes of California’s increasing wildfires.&nbsp;</p>
<p>ArcGIS StoryMaps was chosen as the medium for my project to make it more interactive and to provide more information than I could convey through an infographic. The graphs in my project were created using Python, with coding help from ChatGPT. All maps were made in ArcGIS Pro, with design enhancements made with Adobe Illustrator.&nbsp;</p>
<p>I hope this story can provide a visually compelling and informative look at the causes and effects of California wildfires.</p>
<iframe src="https://storymaps.arcgis.com/stories/d4733f62afe94a1ab81b37e429b072bc" width="100%" height="800px" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="" allow="geolocation">
</iframe>
<p><a href="https://arcg.is/jmnuG1" target="_blank">View Land on Fire in a new tab</a></p>



 ]]></description>
  <category>Interactive</category>
  <category>Thematic</category>
  <guid>https://ian88.github.io/cartography/Land on Fire/</guid>
  <pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://ian88.github.io/cartography/Land on Fire/media/cover.png" medium="image" type="image/png" height="77" width="144"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Mapping California’s Large Wildfires</title>
  <dc:creator>Ian Beilfuss</dc:creator>
  <link>https://ian88.github.io/cartography/Increasing Frequency of Large California Wildfires/</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 




<p>I created this map as the final project for Geography 370: Introduction to Cartography at UW-Madison to draw attention to how the frequency of Wildfires in California has changed from the 20th to the 21st century</p>
<div class="cell">
<div class="cell-output-display">
<div>
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://ian88.github.io/cartography/Increasing Frequency of Large California Wildfires/media/Map.png" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
</div>



 ]]></description>
  <category>Static</category>
  <category>Reference</category>
  <guid>https://ian88.github.io/cartography/Increasing Frequency of Large California Wildfires/</guid>
  <pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2024 06:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://ian88.github.io/cartography/Increasing Frequency of Large California Wildfires/media/cover.png" medium="image" type="image/png" height="153" width="144"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>The Cost of Billion-Dollar Droughts</title>
  <dc:creator>Ian Beilfuss</dc:creator>
  <link>https://ian88.github.io/cartography/The Cost of Billion-Dollar Droughts/</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 




<p>This map was created for a lab assignment in Geography 370: Introduction to Cartography at UW-Madison. The goal of the lab was to create a choropleth map to visualize state spending on drought disasters over the past half century, especially as drought frequency increases due to climate change. I used data from the National Atmospheric and Oceanic Administration and the Bureau of Economic Analysis. GIS analysis was completed in ArcGIS Pro and design enhancements made in Adobe Illustrator.</p>
<div class="cell">
<div class="cell-output-display">
<div>
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://ian88.github.io/cartography/The Cost of Billion-Dollar Droughts/media/Map.jpg" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
</div>



 ]]></description>
  <category>Static</category>
  <category>Thematic</category>
  <guid>https://ian88.github.io/cartography/The Cost of Billion-Dollar Droughts/</guid>
  <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://ian88.github.io/cartography/The Cost of Billion-Dollar Droughts/media/Map.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Mapping Africa’s Physical Geography</title>
  <dc:creator>Ian Beilfuss</dc:creator>
  <link>https://ian88.github.io/cartography/Mapping Africa’s Physical Geography/</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 




<p>This map was created for a lab assignment in Geography 370: Introduction to Cartography at UW-Madison. The goal of the lab was to create a reference map of Africa including all 55 Capital cities, 47 additional cities, 10 marine areas, 5 major rivers, and 55 natural landscape features. I used Adobe Illustrator for a significant portion of this lab to organize all of the labels in a coherent way that maximized clarity. The final reference map is shown below along with the initial version exported from ArcGiS Pro before any label styling and adjustments were completed.</p>
<section id="final-map" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="final-map">Final Map</h2>
<div class="cell">
<div class="cell-output-display">
<div>
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://ian88.github.io/cartography/Mapping Africa’s Physical Geography/media/Map.png" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</section>
<section id="before-label-adjustments" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="before-label-adjustments">Before Label Adjustments</h2>
<div class="cell">
<div class="cell-output-display">
<div>
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://ian88.github.io/cartography/Mapping Africa’s Physical Geography/media/Initial.png" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
</div>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>Static</category>
  <category>Reference</category>
  <guid>https://ian88.github.io/cartography/Mapping Africa’s Physical Geography/</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 14 Oct 2024 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://ian88.github.io/cartography/Mapping Africa’s Physical Geography/media/Map.png" medium="image" type="image/png" height="189" width="144"/>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
